<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>coworkingspaces - Propques</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/coworkingspaces/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/coworkingspaces/</link>
	<description>Premium Coworking Consultancy in India</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:47:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Asset-2.png</url>
	<title>coworkingspaces - Propques</title>
	<link>/tag/coworkingspaces/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Five alternatives to boost your coworking space revenue</title>
		<link>/featured/five-alternatives-to-boost-your-coworking-space-revenue/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=five-alternatives-to-boost-your-coworking-space-revenue</link>
					<comments>/featured/five-alternatives-to-boost-your-coworking-space-revenue/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affordable coworking spaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworking space investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworking spaces in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworkingspaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managedcoworking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to the bright and bouncing-back world of the coworking industry, making high profits is not limited to the desks and Wi-Fi setup alone. It all comes down to thinking outside the box and coming up with pretty intelligent ways for making that extra moolah. Here are five simple ways through which you &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/featured/five-alternatives-to-boost-your-coworking-space-revenue/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Five alternatives to boost your coworking space revenue</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/featured/five-alternatives-to-boost-your-coworking-space-revenue/">Five alternatives to boost your coworking space revenue</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img fetchpriority="high" width="2560" height="1774" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/business-concept-with-graphic-holography-scaled.webp" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #263331;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/business-concept-with-graphic-holography-scaled.webp 2560w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/business-concept-with-graphic-holography-300x208.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/business-concept-with-graphic-holography-1024x709.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/business-concept-with-graphic-holography-768x532.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/business-concept-with-graphic-holography-1536x1064.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/business-concept-with-graphic-holography-2048x1419.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="263331" />
<p>When it comes to the bright and bouncing-back world of the coworking industry, making high profits is not limited to the desks and Wi-Fi setup alone. It all comes down to thinking outside the box and coming up with pretty intelligent ways for making that extra moolah. Here are five simple ways through which you can explain to your coworking space on how best it can derive revenue and stay ahead.</p>



<p>1. Host Fun Events: Make Your Space the Place to Be Turn your coworking space into a cool events spot that people love to visit. From workshops to parties, several other things might be happening in the space, including giving birth to some of the trends.<br><br>By hosting events at the center, they reveal the space not only by renting it but also renting drinks and snacks sold at the occasion and helping in organizing the event. With some clever marketing, your space could become the go-to spot for all kinds of gatherings.</p>



<p>2. Special Membership Offer: Treat Your best customers like vIPs<br></p>



<p>Offer a special membership package to your most valued customers in such a way that makes them feel really special, exceeding the levels of a typical customer. Private desks, inviting space to exclusive events, or personal help when they need it. If people are ready to pay more for privileged treatment, such types of memberships also raise your space&#8217;s revenue.</p>



<p>&nbsp;3.Froster connections and a collaborative environment: Build connections and boost your earnings by collaborating with other businesses. Create exclusive offers for your members, such as discounted gym memberships conveniently located just across the street. Forge partnerships with nearby cafes to ensure that your members always enjoy affordable coffee options. Let&#8217;s foster a community where networking not only leads to friendships but also to financial benefits.</p>



<p>To sum up, by helping you work with others, this section will help you give extra value to your members, and hopefully, earn yourself some extra cash along the way through referral fees and other agreements.</p>



<p>4. Be Flexible: Change with the Times<br><br>The way people work is always changing, so it&#8217;s important to be flexible.Offer different kinds of workspaces, like virtual offices or short-term rentals, which would meet different people&#8217;s needs. Being versatile guarantees that you are occupying 100 percent space, hence an assured opportunity to make that extra dollar around the clock all year.</p>



<p>5. Offer Extra Services: Give People What They Want<br><br>Think of what else your members may need and offer it. They most likely need computer help or would like to learn some new skills. You will also have a chance at earning an extra profit and, in the process, create satisfaction among them through additional services like IT support or workshops.</p>



<p>In summary, therefore, the quest to make more in this business leaves one to have to be creative, work with others, and give people what they want. There are easy approaches for the host of events, special memberships, partnering with others, being flexible, and offering extra services that could help increase revenues and make the coworking space successful.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/featured/five-alternatives-to-boost-your-coworking-space-revenue/">Five alternatives to boost your coworking space revenue</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/featured/five-alternatives-to-boost-your-coworking-space-revenue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
