<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Data Report - Propques</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/data-report/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/data-report/</link>
	<description>Premium Coworking Consultancy in India</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 06:37:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Asset-2.png</url>
	<title>Data Report - Propques</title>
	<link>/category/data-report/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Jaipur, Rajasthan ,India?</title>
		<link>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-jaipur-rajasthan-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-jaipur-rajasthan-india</link>
					<comments>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-jaipur-rajasthan-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We performed a&#160;Coworking Demand Analysis&#160;for a Jaipur, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the next quater Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you. Our Data-Driven Process Propques&#160;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-jaipur-rajasthan-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Jaipur, Rajasthan ,India?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-jaipur-rajasthan-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Jaipur, Rajasthan ,India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img fetchpriority="high" width="1664" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz869264.png" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #899eaf;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz869264.png 1664w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz869264-300x180.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz869264-1024x615.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz869264-768x462.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz869264-1536x923.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1664px) 100vw, 1664px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="899eaf" />
<p>We performed a&nbsp;<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RwCN9rBljGZelS95YA-W2-Em_vbQOraf/view?usp=share_link">Coworking Demand Analysis</a>&nbsp;for a Jaipur, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the next quater Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Our Data-Driven Process</strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to plot out their next locations. We’ve used our experience of operating coworking spaces for 7 years and as market researchers to develop a process and algorithm specifically for the coworking and commercial real estate industry. The datasets uses over 67 detailed buyer and lifestyle profiles and we’ve correlated each profile with successful coworking markets and forward looking trends. Each profile is graded on their likelihood of joining a coworking space and the type of coworking space they would be most interested in.</p>



<p>All of that data is combined with other local factors (density, mode of transportation, education, etc.) that determine the likely success and size of coworking spaces that can be sustained in the area. The result projects how much coworking space can be sustained in the area the type of coworking (High-end Flex, Mid-range Flex, Executive Suite, etc) that will be most in demand.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Jaipur, Rajasthan,India</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQHyYOXKTkxfmA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1667455527652?e=1672876800&amp;v=beta&amp;t=X9LFs3oZ2-Dfzq9J3lu0sDeuhGjqrsxsMuSJcbFhGAw" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Download the full report</figcaption></figure>



<p>Demographics Each pin code’s population is broken down into demographic tapestries that represent the residents’ income and lifestyle.</p>



<p>These are the top 4 for your pin code:</p>



<p><strong>Tonk Road</strong></p>



<p>Tonk Road has bagged the name as the posh residential colony, situated on the Jaipur-Kota National Highway; Tonk Road runs parallel to the neighbourhood of Jagatpura in the south-eastern parts of Jaipur.</p>



<p>Outstanding connectivity to Sitapura Industrial Area and Jaipur International Airport coupled with budget-friendly housing options are the key demand driver of Tonk Road Tonk Road offers excellent connectivity to major employment hubs like RIICO Industrial Area (7Km), Sanganer Industrial Area (6Km), Vishwakarma Industries Association (22Km), Malviya Nagar Industrial Area (10Km), and Sitapura Industrial Area (4Km). The famous Mahindra World City, which comprises of the SEZs, industrial parks are located at a distance of 23 km from the Tonk Road.</p>



<p><em><a href="http://www.propques.com/">Airport: 7.3Km | Railway Station: 14.3Km 47.57%</a><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title=""> </a><a href="http://www.propques.com/">of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded A for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><strong>Vaishali Nagar</strong></p>



<p>Vaishali Nagar is known as the most expensive and well-established residential neighbourhood situated adjacent to the NH-48 in the south-western parts of Jaipur. Superlative physical infrastructure and the presence of civic amenities within the area have made Vaishali Nagar one of the top real estate destinations.</p>



<p>Mahindra World City which is home to the IT/ITes firm like Wipro, Infosys is located at a distance of 20 km from the Vaishali Nagar via NH-48. Moreover, Malviya Nagar Industrial area which hosts Packaging, chemicals, machinery and equipment is located at a distance of 13 km from Vaishali Nagar. Further, Business Park Tower (7Km), Vishwakarma Industries Association (11Km), Malviya Industrial Area (13Km), Sitapura Industrial Area (20Km), Sanganer Industrial Area (13Km) are the major employment hubs that can be easily reached from Vaishali Nagar.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 13 Km | Railway Station: 5 Km 35.47% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded B for coworking compatibility.&nbsp;</a></em></p>



<p><strong>C-Scheme</strong></p>



<p>C-Scheme is one of the prominent and well-known sub-locality of Ashok Nagar located in the north-eastern part of Jaipur. C-Scheme is popular for the white marble Birla Temple, historical monuments, elegant forts, luxury hotels and it mainly comprises high end apartments.</p>



<p>C-Scheme is well-connected to the popular employment hub like Ajmer Road (6Km) via Jaipur Road and Ajmer Road. It has a number of multinational companies like Genpact, Infosys, ICICI Bank, JCB India Ltd, and Wipro. The famous Mahindra World City is 24Km away via National Highway-48. It is home to several prestigious companies such as Genpact, Appirio, Infosys, Wipro, Connexions, Deutsche Bank, GirnarSoft, Nagarro, QH Talbros etc</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 12 Km | Railway Station: 2.7 Km 26.3 7% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded C for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><strong>Mansarovar</strong></p>



<p>Mansarovar is a residential area located in south western parts of Jaipur, which was declared as Asia&#8217;s largest residential colony in 2010. Mansarovar is divided into nine sectors.</p>



<p>Key employment hubs from the locality are RIICO Industrial Area (3Km), Malviya Nagar Industrial Area (9Km), Sitapura Industrial Area (12Km), Business Park Tower (12Km), Mahindra World City (21Km), and Sanganer Industrial Area (5Km).</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 6.7 Km | Railway Station: 12 Km 11.3 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded D for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQFCAjwyrver_A/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1667455932233?e=1672876800&amp;v=beta&amp;t=alun8okXZgCcErk0jgotGvIz-Zg6hHVtO7bDVEsE_08" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Much Flex Office Can Be Sustained in Jaipur?</strong></h3>



<p>Based on our coworking demographic data for the region, Jaipur location, and the cities upward trend,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;predicts the city support 25,200 square feet for next quater Dec-Feb22.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Recommended Coworking Business Model: Mid-Flex &amp; Modern Executive Suite</strong></h3>



<p>A Mid-Flex or Modern Executive Suite will be the most successful types of flexible office space in Jaipur. We have a list of types of properties that these models work well in inside the report.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What can you do with this data?</strong></h3>



<p>The Coworking Demand Analysis report is a great first step to evaluate coworking’s potential for a building you may own or area you are interested in expanded to. It’s an unbiased market research approach to evaluating the potential for a space in a quick and affordable way.</p>



<p>If you are interested to move forward in learning more about coworking’s potential at a location then you’ll likely want to work with a professional and ask about a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Focus and Feasibility Study</a>. The Propques consultant will create a targeted area, evaluate the competition, and build out a business model and P &amp; L based on realistic expectations, data, and experience.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-jaipur-rajasthan-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Jaipur, Rajasthan ,India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-jaipur-rajasthan-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Ahmedabad, Gujrat ,India?</title>
		<link>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-ahmedabad-gujrat-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-ahmedabad-gujrat-india</link>
					<comments>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-ahmedabad-gujrat-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We performed a&#160;Coworking Demand Analysis&#160;for a Ahmedabad, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the next quater Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you. Our Data-Driven Process Propques&#160;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-ahmedabad-gujrat-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Ahmedabad, Gujrat ,India?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-ahmedabad-gujrat-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Ahmedabad, Gujrat ,India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1560" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz194843.png" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #413e3c;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz194843.png 1560w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz194843-300x192.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz194843-1024x656.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz194843-768x492.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz194843-1536x985.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1560px) 100vw, 1560px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="413e3c" />
<p>We performed a&nbsp;<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RwCN9rBljGZelS95YA-W2-Em_vbQOraf/view?usp=share_link">Coworking Demand Analysis</a>&nbsp;for a Ahmedabad, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the next quater Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Our Data-Driven Process</h3>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to plot out their next locations. We’ve used our experience of operating coworking spaces for 7 years and as market researchers to develop a process and algorithm specifically for the coworking and commercial real estate industry. The datasets uses over 67 detailed buyer and lifestyle profiles and we’ve correlated each profile with successful coworking markets and forward looking trends. Each profile is graded on their likelihood of joining a coworking space and the type of coworking space they would be most interested in.</p>



<p>All of that data is combined with other local factors (density, mode of transportation, education, etc.) that determine the likely success and size of coworking spaces that can be sustained in the area. The result projects how much coworking space can be sustained in the area the type of coworking (High-end Flex, Mid-range Flex, Executive Suite, etc) that will be most in demand.</p>



<p><strong>Ahmedabad, Gujrat, India</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQHuvLPk2YJDuA/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0/1668835267190?e=1674691200&amp;v=beta&amp;t=9s51HP3Ff2Pcxy3HTWXGmUwWefrsQdgqef_0Lo8x798" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<p>Demographics Each pin code’s population is broken down into demographic tapestries that represent the residents’ income and lifestyle.</p>



<p>These are the top 5 for your pin code:</p>



<p><strong>Navrangpura&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Navrangpura is a prominent residential cum commercial locality that lies in the western periphery of Ahmedabad. Some of the well-planned residential projects situated in Navrangpura are Merlin Opal, Dharmadev Netra Bungalows, Lakshya Elite 18 Square, Sun Centrum and Alpine Heights.</p>



<p>Navrangpura is surrounded by several residential areas like Usmanpura, Gulbai Tekra, Memnagar, Ambawadi and Vastrapur.The locality is connected to the eastern part of the city via Gandhi Bridge. Municipal Transport Service (AMTS) buses regularly ply through Navrangpura. The Gandhigram Railway Station is located at a short distance of 3Km via Mithakhali Six Road. Navrangpura also have BRTS bus connectivity .</p>



<p>Few renowned business parks which are easily accessible from Navrangpura include Aaryans Corporate Park (8Km), Parshwanath Business Park (10Km), W-2 Samet Business Park (11Km) and Platinum Industrial Park (14Km). The prominent GIDC Industrial Area, Fortune Industrial Park and Shridhar Industrial Park in Odhav Industrial Estate (14Km) are easily accessible from Navrangpura.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 10 Km | Railway Station: 5 Km | 30.68% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded A for coworking compatibility.&nbsp;</a></em></p>



<p><strong>Bodakdev</strong></p>



<p>Bodakdev is a favoured residential destination in Ahmedabad, due to its proximity to the employment hub Satellite-Prahlad Nagar. It is also one of the costliest localities of the city. Bodakdev is surrounded by other prominent localities of Thaltej, South Bopal, Prahlad Nagar and Satellite.</p>



<p>Located on Sarkhej-Gandhinagar Highway, Bodakdev is less than 2 kms from both Sardar Patel Ring Road and 132 Feet Ring Road. Satellite Road, IIM Road, and Drive-In Road are other prominent roads accessible from the locality. Thaltej metro station on the under-construction blue line (East-West Corridor) of Ahmedabad metro is just 2 mins from the locality.</p>



<p>Satellite- Prahlad Nagar isa prime office hub of Ahmedabad within 15 to 20 minutes from Bodakdev. Some of the prominent office complexes in Satellite-Prahalad Nagar are Iscon Emporio, Pinnacle Business Park, Titanium Heights, Westgate Business Bay, and Safal Profitaire.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 16 Km | Railway Station: 11 Km | 27.76 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded B for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><strong>Vastrapur</strong></p>



<p>Vastrapur is a residential neighborhood in the western parts of Ahmedabad. Vastrapur is home to the prestigious educational institute of India, India Institute of Management. Considering its fabulous social infrastructure and affordable housing options, Vastrapur started gaining prominence and demand from a large number of home buyers.</p>



<p>Vastrapur offers easy access to numerous localities like Bodakdev, Mahavir Nagar, Premchand Nagar, Ambawadi and Bopal.Vastrapur is excellently connected to other parts of the city via various significant roads like Vastrapur Road, Sarkari Vasahat Road, IIM Road, and 132 Feet Ring Road.Prime business centres which are easily accessible from this area include Navratna Business Park (3Km), Parshwanath Business park (5Km), Pinnacle Business Park (7Km), and Westgate Business Bay (7Km). Gopinath Industrial Estate is nearly 14Km through Swami Vivekananda Road, and Vatva is approximately 16Km through NH228 and NH64 while Sanand is 21Km via Sarkhej &#8211; Gandhinagar Highway and NH947.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 14 Km | Railway Station: 5 Km | 25.6% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded C for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><strong>Satellite&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Satellite is a well-established and posh residential area situated in the western suburbs of Ahmedabad. Satellite tops the chart for gaining massive real estate demand owing to its well-developed infrastructure development and immediate vicinity to Navratna Business Park.</p>



<p>Satellite shares good connectivity with some of the prime localities like Vastrapur, Bodakdev, Ambawadi, Mumatpura, and Vasna.Sarkhej Gandhinagar Highway and 132 Feet Ring Road are the two significant roads that connect Satellite to various vital parts of Ahmedabad.</p>



<p>Prime business centers like Navratna Business Park (2Km), Parshwanath Business Park (3Km), Pinnacle Business Park (4Km) and Westgate Business Bay (5Km) are easily accessible from this area. Vatva is situated around 16Km via NH64, and Sanand is located approximately 19Km through NH947, while Naroda is 23Km via Airport Road.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 16 Km | Railway Station: 6&nbsp;| 25 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded D for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><strong>Makarba</strong></p>



<p>Makarba is one of the rapidly growing residential areas in the south western part of Ahmedabad. It is placed along the Sardar Patel Ring Road. Proximity to Sarkhej Highway and great approach to tech parks like Infinity Tower s boosting the real estate sector of Makarba.</p>



<p>Makarba enjoys strong connectivity to other parts of the city via Sardar Patel Ring Road and Jawaharlal Nehru Road. Also, Ahmedabad Municipal Transport Service (AMTS) buses are frequently available.</p>



<p>&#8220;Pinnacle Business Park, Synergy Tower and Parshwanath Business Park are located within the vicinity. W-2 Samet Business Park, Platinum Industrial Park and Saffron Business Park are located within 18Km from Makarba. The prominent industrial hubs like Gopinath Industrial Estate (20Km) and GIDC Industrial Area (21Km) can be covered via National Highway-64 and Narol &#8211; Naroda Road from Makarba.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 22 Km | Railway Station: 3 Km | 15 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded E for coworking compatibility</a></em>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQGzRuACAQ7Vpw/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0/1668835999699?e=1674691200&amp;v=beta&amp;t=SLKVcpONbmVzOIv0tiGSfAIolQ3Uuq2naViMKuowQUU" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">How Much Flex Office Can Be Sustained in Ahmedabad?</a></h3>



<p>Based on our coworking demographic data for the region, Ahmedabad location, and the cities upward trend,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;predicts the city support&nbsp;<strong>69615 square feet</strong>&nbsp;for next quater Dec-Feb23.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Recommended Coworking Business Model: Mid-Flex &amp; Modern Executive Suite</h3>



<p>A Mid-Flex or Modern Executive Suite will be the most successful types of flexible office space in Ahmedabad. We have a list of types of properties that these models work well in inside the report.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do with this data?</h3>



<p>The Coworking Demand Analysis report is a great first step to evaluate coworking’s potential for a building you may own or area you are interested in expanded to. It’s an unbiased market research approach to evaluating the potential for a space in a quick and affordable way.</p>



<p>If you are interested to move forward in learning more about coworking’s potential at a location then you’ll likely want to work with a professional and ask about a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Focus and Feasibility Study</a>. The Propques consultant will create a targeted area, evaluate the competition, and build out a business model and P &amp; L based on realistic expectations, data, and experience.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-ahmedabad-gujrat-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Ahmedabad, Gujrat ,India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-ahmedabad-gujrat-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Chandigarh, Punjab ,India?</title>
		<link>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-chandigarh-punjab-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-chandigarh-punjab-india</link>
					<comments>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-chandigarh-punjab-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We performed a&#160;Coworking Demand Analysis&#160;for a Chandigarh, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the next quater Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you. Our Data-Driven Process Propques&#160;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-chandigarh-punjab-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Chandigarh, Punjab ,India?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-chandigarh-punjab-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Chandigarh, Punjab ,India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1560" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz332098.png" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #697174;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz332098.png 1560w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz332098-300x192.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz332098-1024x656.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz332098-768x492.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz332098-1536x985.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1560px) 100vw, 1560px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="697174" />
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/propques/"></a>We performed a&nbsp;<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RwCN9rBljGZelS95YA-W2-Em_vbQOraf/view?usp=share_link">Coworking Demand Analysis</a>&nbsp;for a Chandigarh, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the next quater Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Our Data-Driven Process</h3>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to plot out their next locations. We’ve used our experience of operating coworking spaces for 7 years and as market researchers to develop a process and algorithm specifically for the coworking and commercial real estate industry. The datasets uses over 67 detailed buyer and lifestyle profiles and we’ve correlated each profile with successful coworking markets and forward looking trends. Each profile is graded on their likelihood of joining a coworking space and the type of coworking space they would be most interested in.</p>



<p>All of that data is combined with other local factors (density, mode of transportation, education, etc.) that determine the likely success and size of coworking spaces that can be sustained in the area. The result projects how much coworking space can be sustained in the area the type of coworking (High-end Flex, Mid-range Flex, Executive Suite, etc) that will be most in demand.</p>



<p><strong>Chandigarh, Punjab</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQE2djygIP8J4g/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0/1670561290817?e=1675900800&amp;v=beta&amp;t=m_UCifymrE7bDnUjm4ubHk_6lPmg8X_xrs5glcPT8fA" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<p>Demographics Each pin code’s population is broken down into demographic tapestries that represent the residents’ income and lifestyle.</p>



<p>These are the top 5 for your pin code:</p>



<p><strong>Industrial Phase I &amp; II</strong></p>



<p>Industrial area phase-1 and 2 are the new upcoming areas in Chandigarh for the best office and industrial use. Industrial area not only works but parties too, so to meet that requirement of people we have may party places too.The biggest mall for retail is in industrial area named as elante.Industrial Area Phase 1 is an locality in Chandigarh, Chandigarh Capital Region, India. Sector 27 (2.62 Km), Sector 20 (4.6 Km), Sector 33 (4.62 Km), Sector 8 (5.39 Km) are the nearby areas to Industrial Area Phase 1.. 36% of the properties in Phase I Industrial Area are Commercial Office Space.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 4.5 Km | Railway Station: 3 Km</a></em></p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">35.87% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded A for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Sector 34</strong></p>



<p>Sector-34 is a residential cum commercial area in Chandigarh which grabs high demand due to its proximity to Rajiv Gandhi Chandigarh Technology ParK. Localities enveloped by Sector-34 are Daria, Manimajra, Sahibzada Ajit Singh Nagar, Khudda Lahora, and Sukteri.It is centrally located in Sector 34. Suitable for all kinds of office works, insurance companies, share markets, call centers, immigration offices, spas, salons, coaching centers, laboratories, etc.Sector 36 (1.95 Km), Sector 44 (2.2 Km), Sector 21 (2.24 Km), Sector 43 (2.24 Km), Sector 22 (2.38 Km) are the nearby areas to Sector 34.Tarf Kumbra, Chandigarh, Mohali, Sahibzada Ajit Singh Nagar are the nearby cities to Sector 34.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 17 Km | Railway Station: 7.7 Km</a></p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">25.6% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded B for coworking compatibility.</a></p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Zirakpur</strong></p>



<p>Zirakpur is a residential area located in the eastern parts of Chandigarh. It is situated at a distance of 12 km from the locality and known as the satellite town of Chandigarh. Presence of the affordable housing project and superlative physical infrastructure drive the real estate demand of the Chandigarh. Rajiv Gandhi Chandigarh Technology Park and MK Technology Park are located at a distance of 16Km from Zirakpur. Industrial Area, Phase I which is known for manufacturing sanitary fittings, paper industry, printing, industrial fasteners, steel fabrication, etc., is just 7Km away via Chandigarh Road. Shahibzada Ajit Singh Nagar which is home to top companies like Punjab Tractor Limited (PTL), Quark and Phillips is approximately 18Km through NH5.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 13 Km | Railway Station: 9 Km</a></em></p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">22.67 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded C for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Dera Bassi</strong></p>



<p>BDera Bassi is one of the prominent residential cum commercial location situated in the northern part of Chandigarh. Dera Bassi is a satellite city of Chandigarh, strategically located on the Chandigarh&#8217;s Delhi National Highway. Presence of renowned industries like Molson Coors India, Hella India Lightings.Ltd and excellent connectivity to employment hubs like Mohali are the major factors boosting the residential sector of Dera Bassi. Dera Bassi is home to a number of companies such as Nectar LifeSciences.Ltd, Federal Agro Industries, Ind Swift.Ltd, Winsome Yarns, TSPL, KDDL.Ltd, HPL Additives.Ltd and many more. Furthermore, the popular Rajiv Gandhi Chandigarh Technology Park is located at a distance of 20Km, and can be reached through Ambala-Chandigarh Expressway. It includes renowned companies such as Infosys, Tech Mahindra, Wipro, NetSmartz, IDS Infotech and Net Solutions.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 17 Km | Railway Station: 16 Km</a></p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">20.76 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded D for coworking compatibility.</a></p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Sector 82</strong></p>



<p>sector 82 is a residential project in mohali, making the properties worthy of investment, as it lies in the biggest commercial hub of the city. The locality is surrounded by many facilities such as shopping centers, shopping malls, markets, hospitals, clinics, schools, banks, and atms. the locality has done well with providing various transport options such as autos, taxis, bus stops, and auto stands. this makes the connectivity strong to the other parts of the city. this layout is designed, including shopping malls, hospitals, and several public transportation options, which in return makes connectivity smooth to other parts of the city. sector 82 is surrounded by many other similar localities, which are also known to be well connected to the amenities held around the locality.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 9.6 Km | Railway Station: 13.6 Km</a></em></p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">15 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded E for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQEPHXCylvwuXA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1670561696694?e=1675900800&amp;v=beta&amp;t=jLIneQYDLrHoo1fNlH1_it55bAMpisjXWOcaJjC55XQ" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">How Much Flex Office Can Be Sustained in Chandigarh?</a></h3>



<p>Based on our coworking demographic data for the region, Chandigarh location, and the cities upward trend,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;predicts the city support&nbsp;<strong>52500 square feet</strong>&nbsp;for next quarter Dec-Feb23.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Recommended Coworking Business Model: Mid-Flex &amp; Modern Executive Suite</h3>



<p>A Mid-Flex or Modern Executive Suite will be the most successful types of flexible office space in Ahmedabad. We have a list of types of properties that these models work well in inside the report.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do with this data?</h3>



<p>The Coworking Demand Analysis report is a great first step to evaluate coworking’s potential for a building you may own or area you are interested in expanded to. It’s an unbiased market research approach to evaluating the potential for a space in a quick and affordable way.</p>



<p>If you are interested to move forward in learning more about coworking’s potential at a location then you’ll likely want to work with a professional and ask about a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Focus and Feasibility Study</a>. The Propques consultant will create a targeted area, evaluate the competition, and build out a business model and P &amp; L based on realistic expectations, data, and experience.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-chandigarh-punjab-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Chandigarh, Punjab ,India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-chandigarh-punjab-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh?</title>
		<link>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-lucknow-uttar-pradesh/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-lucknow-uttar-pradesh</link>
					<comments>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-lucknow-uttar-pradesh/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We performed a&#160;Coworking Demand Analysis&#160;for a Lucknow, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you. Our Data-Driven Process Propques&#160;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-lucknow-uttar-pradesh/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-lucknow-uttar-pradesh/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="2080" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz551234.png" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #2b343b;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz551234.png 2080w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz551234-300x144.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz551234-1024x492.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz551234-768x369.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz551234-1536x738.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz551234-2048x985.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2080px) 100vw, 2080px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="2b343b" />
<p>We performed a&nbsp;<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RwCN9rBljGZelS95YA-W2-Em_vbQOraf/view?usp=share_link">Coworking Demand Analysis</a>&nbsp;for a Lucknow, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 22. We have some exciting findings for you.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Our Data-Driven Process</h3>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to plot out their next locations. We’ve used our experience of operating coworking spaces for 7 years and as market researchers to develop a process and algorithm specifically for the coworking and commercial real estate industry. The datasets uses over 67 detailed buyer and lifestyle profiles and we’ve correlated each profile with successful coworking markets and forward looking trends. Each profile is graded on their likelihood of joining a coworking space and the type of coworking space they would be most interested in.</p>



<p>All of that data is combined with other local factors (density, mode of transportation, education, etc.) that determine the likely success and size of coworking spaces that can be sustained in the area. The result projects how much coworking space can be sustained in the area the type of coworking (High-end Flex, Mid-range Flex, Executive Suite, etc) that will be most in demand.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title=""><strong>Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQHJkBR8mMdS5Q/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0/1670841832280?e=1676505600&amp;v=beta&amp;t=RpSFAoeJ1bHvTMmWCzrOxua6xhUGShGORoA0MphGI-o" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<p>Demographics Each pin code’s population is broken down into demographic tapestries that represent the residents’ income and lifestyle.</p>



<p>These are the top 5 for your pin code:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title=""><strong>Gomti Nagar</strong></a></p>



<p>Gomti Nagar is a locality in Lucknow that consists of both residential and businVarious malls in the area are the Fun Republic Mall, the City Mall Lucknow, MOD Plaza, Jeevan Plaza, Wave Mall Lucknow, and the Vijay Shree&#8217;s Antas Shopping Mall and Multiplex. The WEDOST Supermarket is the most famous in the locality. The restaurants that are near the locality are Kathi Rolls and Momos, Paratha Makers Cafe, Magan&#8217;s restaurant, Spice Bowl Restaurant, Sura Vie Lucknow, and many more.ess settlements. The areas that are in the close vicinity of Gomti Nagar, Lucknow are Hazratganj, Indira Nagar, and Aliganj. The HCL IT City, Lucknow, SEZ, Unit-1 is at a distance of 8 KM from Gomti Nagar, Lucknow. It is one of the most prominent IT Parks in the area. The Tata Consultancy Services, Awadh, Campus Office is at a distance of 3.2KM from the locality.</p>



<p><strong><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 21.2 Km | Railway Station: 16.2 Km</a></em></strong></p>



<p><strong><em><a href="http://www.propques.com/">48.47% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded A for coworking compatibility.</a></em></strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title=""><strong>Hazratganj</strong></a></p>



<p>Hazrataganj is a locality that is in the downtown of Lucknow. The areas that are in the vicinity of the locality are Lalbagh that is at a distance of 2.03KM, Lalkuan which is at a distance of 3.45KM from the locality, and Mahanagar that is at a distance of 3.75KM from the locality. This locality is a perfect blend of commercial as well as residential. The NH27 Highway is in the vicinity of Hazratganj, Lucknow. There are various malls in the locality such as the Sahara Ganj Mall, Family Mart Shopping Mall, Phoenix United Mall, Umrao Mall, Emerald Mall, Vishal Mall, Gardens Galleria Mall, and the City Life Mall. There are various supermarkets such as the Diamond Super Market, Ashiana Super Market, and the Happy Super Market. The HCL IT City, Lucknow, SEZ, Unit-1 is one of the prominent IT parks in the locality. The distance of Hazratganj, Lucknow from the locality is 12KM. The Tata Consultancy services Awadh, Campus Office is at a distance of 8KM from the locality. These IT parks add value to the locality.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 16 Km | Railway Station: 4.2 Km</a></em></p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">28.7 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded B for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><a href="http://www.propques.com/"><strong>Aliganj</strong></a></p>



<p>Aliganj is the 2nd largest residential area in Lucknow after Indira-Nagar. Aliganj is located in north eastern part of Lucknow and situated in the Trans Gomti Area of Lucknow. It has become one of the most sought after area due to presence of University and Medical College etc.Aliganj provides immense employment opportunities in private companies like Prajit Pharmaceuticals Pvt. Ltd., Quest Biotech (India), and government offices including Geological Survey of India, UPSC, IMDUP, CPWD, BSNL, PWD, SBI Training Centre etc. These are located 2 &#8211; 4 km from the locality. Apart from these locals travel for work to STPL (Software Technology Parks of India Limited) which about 7 kms from the locality.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 20.3 Km | Railway Station: 6.4 Km</a></em></p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">22.67 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded C for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><a href="http://www.propques.com/"><strong>Alambagh</strong></a></p>



<p>Alambagh is a locality in Kanpur Road in the state of Uttar Pradesh. LDA Colony surrounds the locality at a distance of 1.72KM from Alambagh, Lucknow, Ashiyana, which is at a distance of 3.38KM from the locality, and Aishbagh is at a distance of 5.41KM from the locality. It is a densely populated area that is a blend of residential and commercial.Many malls in the locality, such as the Phoenix United Mall, Emerald Mall, Man Mahesh mall House, Shalimar Mall, and the Ganj Mall. The locality also has many supermarkets such as the Goldi Super Market, The Grofers Market, and the Easyday Supermarket.The HCL IT City, Lucknow, SEZ, Unit-1 is at 16.3KM from the locality. It is one of the most central I.T. parks in the locality. Other than that, the Tata Consultancy, Awadh, Campus Office is at a distance of 15.9KM from the locality. The latter one is held in the same regard as the previous one.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 5.7 Km | Railway Station: Walking Distance</a></em></p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">20.76 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded D for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title=""><strong>Indira Nagar</strong></a></p>



<p>Indira Nagar is a residential locality in the Indian town of Lucknow. Khurram Nagar, Chinhat, Kalyanpur (east), Eldeco Greens, Balmikinagar are the surrounding localities of Indira Nagar. Picnic Spot Road, Chandan Road, Tedhi Pulia Ring Road, Takrohi Road, and Faizabad Road are some of the major roads enhancing the connectivity of the locality to other parts of the city.Indiranagar and Bhootnath Market metro station of the red line metro facility is available in the locality.Gayatri Market, Lekhraj Market, Bhoothnath Market, and Meena Market are the major destinations for daily shopping needs. Prominent hospitals like Sushma Hospital, Jan Kalyan Eye Hospital, CNS Hospital, PGI Hospital Lucknow, Waris Hospital, and Shekhar Hospital are providing healthcare facilities in the locality.Central Institute of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants, Vikas Bhawan, Jan Sampark Karyalaya, U.P State Construction, and Infrastructure Development Corporation Limited, and Vigilance HQ Lucknow are some of the government offices in the locality. Kaizen Infotech Pvt. Ltd, HashTag Labs Pvt. Ltd. (Development Office), MPSoft INFOTECH, Prithvitech Consultants Pvt. Ltd., and OHGOI are some of the IT/ITeS in the neighborhood providing employment opportunities. East India Pharmaceuticals Works Ltd (8 km), Jankipuram Biotech Park (6 km), and Tata Consultancy Services (4 km) are other few business centers that can be reached in less than an hour from the locality.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Airport: 22.6 Km | Railway Station: 11Km</a></em></p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">20 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded E for coworking compatibility.</a></em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQEYt34NG40u5A/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1670842467193?e=1676505600&amp;v=beta&amp;t=hLHsc5BeE65GuZHC8i2FYIYe_r8cVOpswswbl8n2CEU" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">How Much Flex Office Can Be Sustained in Lucknow?</a></h3>



<p>Based on our coworking demographic data for the region, Lucknow location, and the cities upward trend,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;predicts the city support&nbsp;48,300 square feet&nbsp;for next quarter Dec-Feb23.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Recommended Coworking Business Model: Mid-Flex &amp; Modern Executive Suite</h3>



<p>A Mid-Flex or Modern Executive Suite will be the most successful types of flexible office space in Ahmedabad. We have a list of types of properties that these models work well in inside the report.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do with this data?</h3>



<p>The Coworking Demand Analysis report is a great first step to evaluate coworking’s potential for a building you may own or area you are interested in expanded to. It’s an unbiased market research approach to evaluating the potential for a space in a quick and affordable way.</p>



<p>If you are interested to move forward in learning more about coworking’s potential at a location then you’ll likely want to work with a professional and ask about a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Focus and Feasibility Study</a>. The Propques consultant will create a targeted area, evaluate the competition, and build out a business model and P &amp; L based on realistic expectations, data, and experience.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-lucknow-uttar-pradesh/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-lucknow-uttar-pradesh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India?</title>
		<link>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-indore-madhya-pradesh-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-indore-madhya-pradesh-india</link>
					<comments>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-indore-madhya-pradesh-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We performed a&#160;Coworking Demand Analysis&#160;for a Indore, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 23. We have some exciting findings for you. Our Data-Driven Process Propques&#160;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-indore-madhya-pradesh-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-indore-madhya-pradesh-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1848" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz858069.png" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #9e9a95;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz858069.png 1848w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz858069-300x162.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz858069-1024x554.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz858069-768x416.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz858069-1536x831.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1848px) 100vw, 1848px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="9e9a95" />
<p>We performed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Coworking Demand Analysis</a>&nbsp;for a Indore, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 23. We have some exciting findings for you.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Our Data-Driven Process</h3>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to plot out their next locations. We’ve used our experience of operating coworking spaces for 7 years and as market researchers to develop a process and algorithm specifically for the coworking and commercial real estate industry. The datasets uses over 67 detailed buyer and lifestyle profiles and we’ve correlated each profile with successful coworking markets and forward looking trends. Each profile is graded on their likelihood of joining a coworking space and the type of coworking space they would be most interested in.</p>



<p>All of that data is combined with other local factors (density, mode of transportation, education, etc.) that determine the likely success and size of coworking spaces that can be sustained in the area. The result projects how much coworking space can be sustained in the area the type of coworking (High-end Flex, Mid-range Flex, Executive Suite, etc) that will be most in demand.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Indore, Madhya Pradesh</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQEK1GbXzcmxCA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1671180539205?e=1677110400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=XJc8pyiIVfs8_HxaA88SIOxIyCBZTW8NyjdtPmi6oHI" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<p>Demographics</p>



<p>Each pin code’s population is broken down into demographic tapestries that represent the residents’ income and lifestyle. These are the top 5 for your pin code:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Vijay Nagar</a></p>



<p>Vijay Nagar is a major residential cum commercial area nestled in the eastern part of Bhopal. Vijay Nagar is situated between MR-9, MR-10, and Eastern Ring Road. Vijay Nagar is surrounded by well-known suburbs such as Sukhliya, Palasia and Khajrana Temple Area. Vijay Nagar comprises IDA flats and several private societies. Vijay Nagar is home to several commercial activities like malls, restaurants, hotels and high-end shopping plazas. These includes C-21, Malhar Mega Mall, KFC, McDonald&#8217;s, Dominos, Marriott and Sayaji Hotel. The Pakiza Business Park lies within the vicinity. Famous tech parks like IT Park Pardesipura (4Km) and Crystal IT Park (12Km) are easily accessible. Vijay Nagar is well-connected to the Pithampur industrial area (36Km) via Indore &#8211; Dhar Road which is home to a number of large scale industries and public sector undertakings.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>Airport: 13 Km | Railway Station: 6.7 Km</em></p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>45.87% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded A for coworking compatibility.</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Race Course Road</a></p>



<p>Race Course Road is a prime road has high commercial and residential value. It is very near to bus stand and railway station. The road houses many banking and financial institutions and retail garment chains. It is a clear wide bond road developed by IMC recently.It&#8217;s surrounded by basketball complex, international cricket stadium, Yashwant club, tennis club etc.There is excellent connectivity to various parts of the city, with the availability of various other public modes of transport such as buses, taxis, and autos.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 7.5 Km | Railway Station: 1.2 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>25.6% of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded B for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Scheme No. 78</a></p>



<p>Scheme No. 78 is a developing suburb located in the Indore city of Madhya Pradesh that has many residential projects and commercial spaces taking base here. the locality becomes amongst the top choices for working professionals to settle here as work-to-back-home travel becomes extremely convenient. There are also a number of entertainment zones, shopping centers and recreational areas located in close proximity, which is thus making Scheme No. 78 a hot spot for Real Estate developers and investors.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 14.3 Km | Railway Station: 7.9 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>22.67 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded C for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">New Palasiya</a></p>



<p>New Palasia is a developed residential locality in Indore, situated along the AB Road. Residential developments in the locality majorly comprise of multi-storey apartments. The residential demand in this area is driven by excellent civic amenities; along with proximity to retail infrastructure, railway station, and employment hubs. New Palasia adjoins the prominent and up market areas of South Tukoganj, Shanti Nagar, and Shanti Nagar. New Palasia has good connectivity to the major areas of Indore through the AB Road, Mahatma Gandhi Road, Race Course Road, and RS Bhandari Marg. Further, it has an easy access to the Dewas Road, Bhopal Road, and the Eastern Ring Road that connect to other residential and commercial areas in and around Indore.New Palasia is in proximity of the Electronic Complex, Sanwer Road Industrial Area, and the IT hub of Bhanwar Kuan that houses the Crystal IT Park, Atulya IT Park, and New IT Park.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 8.2 Km | Railway Station: 2 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>20.76 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded D for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Regal Square</a></p>



<p>This square has a statue of Mahatma Gandhi in it&#8217;s centre signifying its presence on M.G. Road. It has got its name from Regal Cinema Hall which is situated in North West direction of the square. It apparently divides old part of Indore to its new part.If you are planning to set up a flourishing business and looking for an appropriate location to initiate the same, then you are at the right place. Situated in the heart of the city is a newly constructed massive commercial office space available. Grab the unique opportunity to set up your business in the prime location. The area enjoys a favorable location with many important commercial establishments in the vicinityone of the famous commercial road of Indore. Having huge business opportunities full of big multistorey, commercial building, shopping malls, showrooms, and many more. Many hotels are also over there. Near to railway &amp; bus station. Near to M G Road, Palasia, Race Course Road, Siyaganj and Chhavni.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 9.6 Km | Railway Station: Walking Distance</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>15 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded E for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQHzYpHrDALaIA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1671180988148?e=1677110400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=u9i1s7Sr3kmsTMf-pjw7Pt5ZAsZeGmosdBlXETKY2tw" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">How Much Flex Office Can Be Sustained in Indore?</a></h3>



<p>Based on our coworking demographic data for the region, Indore location, and the city upward trend,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.propques.com/">Propques</a>&nbsp;predicts the city support&nbsp;38,760 square feet&nbsp;for next quarter Dec-Feb23.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Recommended Coworking Business Model: Mid-Flex &amp; Modern Executive Suite</a></p>
</blockquote>



<p>A Mid-Flex or Modern Executive Suite will be the most successful types of flexible office space in Indore. We have a list of types of properties that these models work well in inside the report.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What can you do with this data?</h3>



<p>The Coworking Demand Analysis report is a great first step to evaluate coworking’s potential for a building you may own or area you are interested in expanded to. It’s an unbiased market research approach to evaluating the potential for a space in a quick and affordable way.</p>



<p>If you are interested to move forward in learning more about coworking’s potential at a location then you’ll likely want to work with a professional and ask about a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Focus and Feasibility Study</a>. The Propques consultant will create a targeted area, evaluate the competition, and build out a business model and P &amp; L based on realistic expectations, data, and experience.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-indore-madhya-pradesh-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-indore-madhya-pradesh-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Kochi, Kerala, India?</title>
		<link>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-kochi-kerala-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-kochi-kerala-india</link>
					<comments>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-kochi-kerala-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We performed a&#160;Coworking Demand Analysis&#160;for a Kochi city, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 23. We have some exciting findings for you. Our Data-Driven Process Propques&#160;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-kochi-kerala-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Kochi, Kerala, India?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-kochi-kerala-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Kochi, Kerala, India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1692" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz271649.png" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #cbd7e8;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz271649.png 1692w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz271649-300x177.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz271649-1024x605.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz271649-768x454.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz271649-1536x908.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1692px) 100vw, 1692px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="cbd7e8" />
<p>We performed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/">Coworking Demand Analysis</a>&nbsp;for a Kochi city, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 23. We have some exciting findings for you.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Our Data-Driven Process</strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/">Propques</a>&nbsp;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to plot out their next locations. We’ve used our experience of operating coworking spaces for 7 years and as market researchers to develop a process and algorithm specifically for the coworking and commercial real estate industry. The datasets uses buyer and lifestyle profiles and we’ve correlated each profile with successful coworking markets and forward looking trends. Each profile is graded on their likelihood of joining a coworking space and the type of coworking space they would be most interested in.</p>



<p>All of that data is combined with other local factors (density, mode of transportation, education, etc.) that determine the likely success and size of coworking spaces that can be sustained in the area. The result projects how much coworking space can be sustained in the area the type of coworking (High-end Flex, Mid-range Flex, Executive Suite, etc) that will be most in demand.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Kochi, Kerala</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQExcy_cJZYenA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1671529446082?e=1677110400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=_ryhb7WGv-76XW7KiFH3VIaBxDDrOuPtjxaSt_e59Zg" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<p><strong>Demographics</strong></p>



<p>Each pin code’s population is broken down into demographic tapestries that represent the residents’ income and lifestyle. These are the top 4 for your pin code:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Kakkanad</a></p>



<p>Located in the eastern part of the Kochi, Kakkanad is an important industrial and residential area in Kochi, Kerala. The presence of numerous industries in the locality has increased the need for residential houses near to the workplace. Some of the surrounding suburbs of Kakkanad are Ernakulam, Puthenkurish, Edappally, and Kamalassery.With big business and five-star hotels, Kakkada is transforming into an important commercial hub. Smart City Kochi is located in Kakkanad is one of the major SEZ projects which is under development and is likely to be completed by 2023. Kakkanad is also home for a Software Export Promotion Zone (SEPZ) which consists of companies like Cognizant, Williamslea, WRENCH Solutions, and others. The Muthoot Technopolis, Parsvanath IT Park, and Trans-Asia Tech Tower are a few other IT Parks providing job opportunities.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 24 Km | Railway Station: 9.2 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>45.56 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded A for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/start-coworking-business/">EnraKulam</a></p>



<p>Ernakulam is a serene and calm suburb in Ernakulam district of Kerala. Ernakulam is surrounded by Vazhoor Taluk towards East, Ettumanoor Taluk towards West, Lalam Taluk towards North and Erattupetta Taluk towards South. Palai, Erattupetta, Kottayam, Changanassery are the nearby cities to Ernakulam. The roads connected to this place are Kumaranasan Road, Gandhi Nagar Road and Kaloor-Kadavanthara Road which are linked to the entire city. This place lies on the border of Kottayam and Pathanamthitta districts, thus allowing easy access to both these areas. Kottayam Railway Station is major railway station near to Ernakulam. Educational Institutions situated in Elamkulam include Kuriakose Gregorios College, Pampady, Mattakkara Hs Mattakkara, St Joseph Girls Hs Mattakkara, St Alosious Hs Manalumkal and St Antonys Ups Paduva. Vicinity. The locality is well developed with many eateries and restaurants in the vicinity like Vinayaka Kalyana Mandapam, which makes Ernakulam all the more relaxing and pleasant.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 27.7 Km | Railway Station: 2.9 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>30.76 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded B for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/start-coworking-business/">Edappally</a></p>



<p>Edappally or Idappalli is a major commercial and a residential region in Kochi. It is surrounded by Elamakkara, Kakkanad, Eloor, Kalamaserry, and Mathurapalli. With renowned hospitals and educational facilities in the neighborhood, the local social and retail infrastructure is strong.Reliance Corporate IT Park and the CITTIC, Technology Business Incubator are the major IT hubs in the Edappally region. Caxita Tech Solutions, Aashrami Consulting and Technology Pvt Ltd, Iga Tech Industrial Electronics Pvt Ltd, and Markuplab Technologies (P) Ltd. are few IT/ITeS providing employment opportunities in the locality. Info Park Technology Business Centre (6 km), Muthoot Technopolis (6 km), C-SiS, CUSAT Science Park (4 km), and KINFRA Hi-Tech Park (7 km) are the few other tech parks in the neighboring localities which can be reached in half an hour. Also, many industries like Eveready Industries India Limited, JK Tyre &amp; INDUSTRIES LTD, Vijo Plastic Industries, and Mareena Petro Chemicals Private Limited provide various job prospects.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 22 Km | Railway Station: 8 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>24.37 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded C for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/start-coworking-business/">Panampilly Nagar</a></p>



<p>PatPanampilly Nagar is a very best locality. It is close to the Railway Station, Bus stand, city, bus stop, temples/churches, schools (BVM, KV etc.), hospitals (Medical Trust, Indira Gandhi), proposed metro, Kadavnatra market etc. It has wide roads, which most localities in Ernakulam cannot claim. It has its own shopping complex and several boutiques, fine dining restaurantsa prestigious residential location is gradually turning to be a favored spot for offices and business houses. The now-crowded area of Panampilly Nagar was once barren and muddy land. Only a part of the locality was used for cultivation.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 33 Km | Railway Station: 3 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>16,76 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded D for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQFBxQC_XVN9Hw/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1671529907909?e=1677110400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=4OSjiWjZ99GPWxZVAgzSqZylutEAMXslZiyTohm5N4I" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/"><strong>How Much Flex Office Can Be Sustained in Kochi?</strong></a></h3>



<p>Based on our coworking demographic data for the region, Kochi location, and the city upward trend,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/">Propques</a>&nbsp;predicts the city support&nbsp;33,880 square feet&nbsp;for next quarter Dec-Feb23.</p>



<p>A Mid-Flex or Modern Executive Suite will be the most successful types of flexible office space in Kochi. We have a list of types of properties that these models work well in inside the report.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/start-coworking-business/"><strong>What can you do with this data?</strong></a></h3>



<p>The Coworking Demand Analysis report is a great first step to evaluate coworking’s potential for a building you may own or area you are interested in expanded to. It’s an unbiased market research approach to evaluating the potential for a space in a quick and affordable way.</p>



<p>If you are interested to move forward in learning more about coworking’s potential at a location then you’ll likely want to work with a professional and ask about a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/">Focus and Feasibility Study</a>. The Propques consultant will create a targeted area, evaluate the competition, and build out a business model and P &amp; L based on realistic expectations, data, and experience.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-kochi-kerala-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Kochi, Kerala, India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-kochi-kerala-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Coimbatore, India?</title>
		<link>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-coimbatore-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-coimbatore-india</link>
					<comments>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-coimbatore-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We performed a&#160;Coworking Demand Analysis&#160;for a Coimbatore city, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 23. We have some exciting findings for you. Our Data-Driven Process Propques&#160;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-coimbatore-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Coimbatore, India?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-coimbatore-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Coimbatore, India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1564" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz569874.png" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #cad2d8;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz569874.png 1564w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz569874-300x192.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz569874-1024x655.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz569874-768x491.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/7xm.xyz569874-1536x982.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1564px) 100vw, 1564px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="cad2d8" />
<p>We performed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/"><strong>Coworking Demand Analysis</strong></a>&nbsp;for a Coimbatore city, Main neighborhood to understand what is and is going to be the most in demand types of coworking for the Dec-Feb 23. We have some exciting findings for you.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Our Data-Driven Process</strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/"><strong>Propques</strong></a>&nbsp;unique formulas and tool sets use the dynamic datasets that McDonald’s, Target, and Starbucks use to plot out their next locations. We’ve used our experience of operating coworking spaces for 7 years and as market researchers to develop a process and algorithm specifically for the coworking and commercial real estate industry. The datasets uses buyer and lifestyle profiles and we’ve correlated each profile with successful coworking markets and forward looking trends. Each profile is graded on their likelihood of joining a coworking space and the type of coworking space they would be most interested in.</p>



<p>All of that data is combined with other local factors (density, mode of transportation, education, etc.) that determine the likely success and size of coworking spaces that can be sustained in the area. The result projects how much coworking space can be sustained in the area the type of coworking (High-end Flex, Mid-range Flex, Executive Suite, etc) that will be most in demand.</p>



<p><a href="http://www.propques.com/">Coimbatore</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQFzH1NKNVg7rA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1671772501530?e=1677110400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=dVe77GxfaslRYOyfjsodoOMnW1QzSCLEzdkxGEwb5yo" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<p><strong>Demographics</strong></p>



<p>Each pin code’s population is broken down into demographic tapestries that represent the residents’ income and lifestyle. These are the top 4 for your pin code:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Saravanampatty</a></p>



<p>It is a prime Locality near prozone Mall, saravanampatti. Best for residential and office purpose. 100 meters from prozone Mall. 100 meters from coimbatore- sathyamabgalam highway. Near schools, colleges, banks, departmental stores and corporate offices. Interested buyers mostly welcome.he Defence SEZ is just 12 km from Saravanampatty. Due to average personal income in Saravanampatty locality is more since more concentration of high net worth individuals are residing here. The service sector is growing fast in this locality. Leading international schools in and around saravanampatty gives clear view of the locality advantage. It is one of the fast-growing neighborhoods of Coimbatore, because of invasion of IT companies surrounding and education institutions. Major IT Companies located in Saravanampatti. Amazon, Bosch, Cognizant, Dell, Ford, HCL and Altran Technologies.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 9.5 Km | Railway Station: 11.2 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>43.46 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded A for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Ganapathy</a></p>



<p>Ganapathy is a densely populated residential cum commercial locality in Coimbatore. Bharati Nagar, Sri Shivasakthi Nagar, Shivaram Nagar, Ganapathi Maanagar are some of the nearby localities. Proximity to the airport, employment hubs like Tidal Park, and good social and retail infrastructure are fueling the real estate growth in this area.Prominent employment hubs like Tidal Park (3km), KCT Tech Park (7km), Chil SEZ IT Park (9km), Target Tech Park (9km), among others are located in the vicinity. Apart from these IT tech park industrial estate such as SIDCO Industrial Estate (17km) and COMSIA Industrial Estate (21km) that comprises of many small and medium scale industries are also increasing employment opportunities.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 9.8 Km | Railway Station: 5 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>38.56 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded B for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Gandhipuram</a></p>



<p>EGandhipuram is a residential cum commercial neighborhood located in the center of Coimbatore. It is a major hub for the intracity bus nodal services. The locality is strategically located close to It is surrounded by localities like Ram Nagar, Tatabad, Rathinapuri, PN Palayam, Sidhapudur, and Sivananda Colony. Prominent shopping avenues, proximity to IT tech parks like KCT Tech Park, and excellent connectivity by road and rail links are driving the growth of real estate. Prominent employment zones such as Tidal Park Coimbatore IT Wing SEZ, Elcot SEZ, KCT Tech Park, Chil SEZ IT Park, among others are located within 8-11 km. These tech parks are home to corporate companies like Wipro, HCL, Bosch, Aricent, among others. Along with these IT parks, there is industrial estate such as Anna Industrial Estate (1km), SIDCO Pvt Industrial Estate (9km), etc. that are boosting employment opportunities.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 10 Km | Railway Station: 3.9 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>27.84 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded C for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Kalapatti</a></p>



<p>Kalapatti is a rapidly growing residential cum industrial locality. It is situated in the north-east region of Coimbatore. Balaji Nagar, Veeriampalayam, Kaikolapalayam, SS Kulam are some of the nearby localities. Proximity to airport, increase in employment hubs such as Global Tech Park and well-connected to NH 47, NH 209, and SH 678 are driving the real estate growth in this area. Casagrand Nextown, KR Villa Park, Sakthi Arum Lily Villa are some of the key residential projects in this area.Kalapatti is home to many machining and motor industries. Motor pump set brands such as Sharp, Ventura, Point, and Fisher have units here. Along with these Indus Electronics India Ltd and Hykon India Ltd, a solar water factory is also located here. Furthermore, IT tech parks such as Global Tech Park (1km), KCT Tech Park (7km), Chil SEZ (8km), Tidal Park (8km), among others are located in the vicinity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Airport: 5.5 Km | Railway Station: 13.3 Km</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>15.76 % of your area&#8217;s population falls in this category. This segment is graded D for coworking compatibility.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D5612AQGCa1F9DUiNNA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1671772959455?e=1677110400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=5ASc4oRYJ83GnnKgY6Lw3qnYNNCDriAAmoLVu8WyvGg" alt="No alt text provided for this image"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/"><strong>How Much Flex Office Can Be Sustained in Coimbatore?</strong></a></h3>



<p>Based on our coworking demographic data for the region, Coimbatore location, and the city upward trend,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/"><strong>Propques</strong></a>&nbsp;predicts the city support&nbsp;44,138 square feet&nbsp;for next quarter Dec-Feb23.</p>



<p>A Mid-Flex or Modern Executive Suite will be the most successful types of flexible office space in Coimbatore. We have a list of types of properties that these models work well in inside the report.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/start-coworking-business/"><strong>What can you do with this data?</strong></a></h3>



<p>The Coworking Demand Analysis report is a great first step to evaluate coworking’s potential for a building you may own or area you are interested in expanded to. It’s an unbiased market research approach to evaluating the potential for a space in a quick and affordable way.</p>



<p>If you are interested to move forward in learning more about coworking’s potential at a location then you’ll likely want to work with a professional and ask about a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/"><strong>Focus and Feasibility Study</strong></a>. The Propques consultant will create a targeted area, evaluate the competition, and build out a business model and P &amp; L based on realistic expectations, data, and experience.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-coimbatore-india/">Feasibility Snapshot: What’s the Coworking Demand in Coimbatore, India?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/data-report/feasibility-snapshot-whats-the-coworking-demand-in-coimbatore-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
