<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Planning - Propques</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/planning/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/planning</link>
	<description>Premium Coworking Consultancy in India</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 06:10:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Asset-2.png</url>
	<title>Planning - Propques</title>
	<link>/blog/category/planning</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How Virtual offices can be a hurdle for coworking spaces?</title>
		<link>/featured/how-virtual-offices-can-be-a-hurdle-for-coworking-spaces/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-virtual-offices-can-be-a-hurdle-for-coworking-spaces</link>
					<comments>/featured/how-virtual-offices-can-be-a-hurdle-for-coworking-spaces/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworking spaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coworking vs virtual offices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual office impact coworking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual office vs shared workspace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual offices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The concept of working from virtual offices has become the new normal. The setup is digitized so that one can work from absolutely anywhere while projecting a professional view. This trend challenges the coworking industry in spaces known as &#8220;the communal work hubs where people and small businesses come together,&#8221; as the dictionary defines them. &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/featured/how-virtual-offices-can-be-a-hurdle-for-coworking-spaces/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How Virtual offices can be a hurdle for coworking spaces?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/featured/how-virtual-offices-can-be-a-hurdle-for-coworking-spaces/">How Virtual offices can be a hurdle for coworking spaces?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img fetchpriority="high" width="2560" height="1707" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/team-working-by-group-video-call-share-ideas-brainstorming-negotiating-use-video-conference-scaled.webp" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #8a898d;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/team-working-by-group-video-call-share-ideas-brainstorming-negotiating-use-video-conference-scaled.webp 2560w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/team-working-by-group-video-call-share-ideas-brainstorming-negotiating-use-video-conference-300x200.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/team-working-by-group-video-call-share-ideas-brainstorming-negotiating-use-video-conference-1024x683.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/team-working-by-group-video-call-share-ideas-brainstorming-negotiating-use-video-conference-768x512.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/team-working-by-group-video-call-share-ideas-brainstorming-negotiating-use-video-conference-1536x1024.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/team-working-by-group-video-call-share-ideas-brainstorming-negotiating-use-video-conference-2048x1365.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="8a898d" />
<p>The concept of working from virtual offices has become the new normal. The setup is digitized so that one can work from absolutely anywhere while projecting a professional view. This trend challenges the coworking industry in spaces known as &#8220;the communal work hubs where people and small businesses come together,&#8221; as the dictionary defines them. Look at how virtual offices are damaging coworking spaces and how they can be mitigated.</p>



<p><strong>The Decline in Membership: Empty Desks and Diminishing Foot Traffic</strong></p>



<p>Many coworking spaces are losing memberships as the pool of<a href="/"> virtual offices</a> grows and becomes a rising trend.</p>



<p>People are going contemporary, finding it more comfortable to work from wherever they are and prefer to avoid signing up for a physical office. This leaves many coworking spaces with empty desks, low foot traffic, and non-vibrancy.</p>



<p><strong>Disruption in the Coworking Landscape: Shifting Demands and Expectations</strong></p>



<p>With its members&#8217; changing needs and expectations, coworking spaces still have to align themselves with the new norm of a virtual office. This attractiveness of remote work is forcing rethinking among most people and companies about the need for physical office spaces, and the trend has resulted in falling numbers of members at traditional coworking spaces.</p>



<p>That will make hybrid work models, which meld full-time and part-time remote and in-person collaboration for coworking spaces, all the more confusing.</p>



<p><strong>Competition for Clients: Losing the Battle for Business</strong></p>



<p>Virtual offices have made the competition tough for coworking spaces to attract customers. This has now become a phenomenon that benefits businesses and freelancers not attached to a location. It has increased the scramble of the coworking spaces to keep their existing clientele and draw new faces—a hard business landscape for them.</p>



<p><strong>The strain on Community Dynamics: Fracturing the Sense of Community</strong></p>



<p>The latter form of coworking spaces is driven by community interaction and collaboration in a way that, at times, unfails the virtual offices in their wake. This is so because, with less physical human presence, there is reduced camaraderie and a general sense of purpose, often leaving a gap among the members and diluting the vibrant atmosphere of coworking spaces.</p>



<p><strong>Financial Pressures: Tightening Budgets and Tough Decisions</strong></p>



<p>The virtual office has quite an economic effect on coworking. This must modulate with a dwindling membership at the coworking space and increasing competition, which now leads to an increasing financial heat. This leaves them making hard decisions on strict mechanisms that cut costs and pricing strategies to survive in a hostile market.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.cubispace.com/">Navigating the Virtual Office Storm</a></strong></p>



<p>It could also test for the opportunity to think innovatively and adaptively in the face of several challenges, such as plummeting membership, financial strains, and community dynamics.</p>



<p>This leaves plenty of room to define the value proposition further, strengthen community relationships, and find new revenue potentials so that coworking spaces can compete with virtual offices head-on and emerge all the better and more durable for it in this ever-evolving modern work environment.</p>



<p>However, virtual offices provide firm challenges, but they also offer opportunities for innovation and adaptation to coworking spaces. This is done through understanding how the dynamic needs of the members can satisfy the improvement of the level of community participation and using technology to improve the service of the workplace.</p>



<p>Ultimately, therefore, coworking spaces can continue to flourish amidst the current thrust in the landscape of modern work by accepting this change while at the same time remaining true to their central values of collaboration and community.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/featured/how-virtual-offices-can-be-a-hurdle-for-coworking-spaces/">How Virtual offices can be a hurdle for coworking spaces?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/featured/how-virtual-offices-can-be-a-hurdle-for-coworking-spaces/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Reasons to Invest in Coworking Spaces in 2023</title>
		<link>/planning/top-5-reasons-to-invest-in-coworking-spaces-in-2023/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=top-5-reasons-to-invest-in-coworking-spaces-in-2023</link>
					<comments>/planning/top-5-reasons-to-invest-in-coworking-spaces-in-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 08:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworking investment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coworking spaces have become increasingly popular in recent years, as more and more people move away from traditional office settings. Coworking spaces offer a number of advantages for businesses of all sizes, including flexibility, affordability, and a sense of community. If you&#8217;re considering investing in a coworking space, there are a few things you need &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/planning/top-5-reasons-to-invest-in-coworking-spaces-in-2023/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Top 5 Reasons to Invest in Coworking Spaces in 2023</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/top-5-reasons-to-invest-in-coworking-spaces-in-2023/">Top 5 Reasons to Invest in Coworking Spaces in 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="830" height="450" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/sdsdd4Asset-3-50-jpg.webp" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #425e4a;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/sdsdd4Asset-3-50-jpg.webp 830w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/sdsdd4Asset-3-50-300x163.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/sdsdd4Asset-3-50-768x416.webp 768w" sizes="(max-width: 830px) 100vw, 830px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="425e4a" />
<p>Coworking spaces have become increasingly popular in recent years, as more and more people move away from traditional office settings. Coworking spaces offer a number of advantages for businesses of all sizes, including flexibility, affordability, and a sense of community.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re considering <a href="/2023/08/18/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/" data-type="link" data-id="/2023/08/18/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>investing in a coworking space</strong></a>, there are a few things you need to know. In this blog post, we&#8217;ll discuss the top five reasons why investing in a coworking space in 2023 is a smart move.</p>



<p><strong>1. Coworking spaces are a growing trend</strong></p>



<p>The coworking industry is growing rapidly and is expected to continue to grow in the coming years. This is due to a number of factors, including the rise of remote work, the increasing number of freelancers and entrepreneurs, and the need for more flexible workspaces.</p>



<p>As the coworking industry continues to grow, so too will the demand for coworking spaces. This means that investors in coworking spaces can expect to see good returns on their investment.</p>



<p><strong>2. Coworking spaces are affordable</strong></p>



<p>Coworking spaces are a more affordable option than traditional office space. This is because coworking spaces typically offer a variety of membership options, so businesses can choose the option that best fits their needs and budget.</p>



<p>In addition, coworking spaces typically include all of the amenities that businesses need, such as high-speed internet, conference rooms, and printing services. This means that businesses don&#8217;t have to worry about incurring additional costs for these amenities.</p>



<p><strong>3. Coworking spaces offer flexibility</strong></p>



<p><a href="/2023/05/05/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/" data-type="link" data-id="/2023/05/05/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Coworking spaces offer</strong></a> businesses a great deal of flexibility. Businesses can rent a desk, a private office, or a team space for as long or as short as they need. This flexibility is especially appealing to businesses that are growing or downsizing, or that need to move frequently.</p>



<p>In addition, coworking spaces typically offer flexible hours, so businesses can come and go as they need. This is ideal for businesses with employees who work different hours or need to meet with clients outside of traditional business hours.</p>



<p><strong>4. Coworking spaces provide a sense of community</strong></p>



<p><a href="/blog/how-to-obtain-a-coworking-franchise-in-india/" data-type="link" data-id="/blog/how-to-obtain-a-coworking-franchise-in-india/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Coworking spaces</strong></a> provide businesses with a sense of community. Coworkers come from a variety of industries and backgrounds, which can lead to new ideas, partnerships, and collaborations.</p>



<p>Coworking spaces also typically host events and workshops, which can help businesses learn new skills and network with other professionals.</p>



<p><strong>5. Coworking spaces are environmentally friendly</strong></p>



<p>Coworking spaces are typically more environmentally friendly than traditional office spaces. This is because coworking spaces are typically shared by multiple businesses, which reduces the amount of energy and resources that are consumed.</p>



<p>In addition, coworking spaces often have sustainable features, such as recycled materials, energy-efficient appliances, and natural light.</p>



<p><strong>How to invest in a coworking space</strong></p>



<p>If you&#8217;re interested in investing in a coworking space, there are a few things you need to do.</p>



<p>First, you need to research the coworking industry and identify the market opportunity in your area. You also need to develop a business plan and determine how you will finance your investment.</p>



<p>Once you have a business plan in place, you need to find a suitable location for your coworking space. The location should be centrally located and easily accessible by public transportation. It should also be in a safe and desirable neighborhood.</p>



<p>Once you have found a location, you need to build out your coworking space. This will involve furnishing the space and providing the necessary amenities, such as high-speed internet, conference rooms, and printing services.</p>



<p>Finally, you need to market your coworking space to potential members. You can do this through online and offline marketing channels.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>Investing in a coworking space can be a smart move for a number of reasons. Coworking spaces are a growing trend, they are affordable, they offer flexibility, they provide a sense of community, and they are environmentally friendly.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re considering investing in a coworking space, be sure to do your research and develop a business plan. You must also find a suitable location and build out your coworking space with the necessary amenities. Finally, you need to market your coworking space to potential members.</p>



<p><strong>Additional tips for investing in a coworking space</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Target a specific niche.</strong>&nbsp;There are many different <a href="/blog/most-common-demographics-of-coworking-space-users/amp/" data-type="link" data-id="/blog/most-common-demographics-of-coworking-space-users/amp/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>types of coworking spaces</strong></a>, such as spaces for freelancers, entrepreneurs, and startups. By targeting a specific niche, you can better cater to the needs of your members.</li>



<li><strong>Offer a variety of membership options.</strong>&nbsp;This will make your coworking space more appealing to a wider range of businesses.</li>



<li><strong>Create a strong community.</strong>&nbsp;Coworking spaces are more than just shared workspaces. They are also places where people can come together to collaborate, network</li>
</ul>


<div class="saswp-faq-block-section"><ol style="list-style-type:none"><li style="list-style-type: none"><h5 class="saswp-faq-question-title">Does coworking space make money?</h5><p class="saswp-faq-answer-text">Yes, coworking spaces can make money. In fact, the coworking industry is growing rapidly and is expected to continue to grow in the coming years. This is due to a number of factors, including the rise of remote work, the increasing number of freelancers and entrepreneurs, and the need for more flexible workspaces.<br>The main source of revenue for coworking spaces is the rental of desks, meeting rooms, and private offices. Coworking spaces also generate revenue from other sources, such as event rentals, food and beverage sales, and merchandise sales.<br>The profitability of a coworking space depends on a number of factors, including the size of the space, the location, the amenities offered, and the pricing structure. However, a well-run coworking space can be a very profitable business.<br>According to a study by DeskMag, the average profit margin for coworking spaces is around 10%. However, some coworking spaces are even more profitable, with margins of up to 20%.</p><li style="list-style-type: none"><h5 class="saswp-faq-question-title">Is coworking space profitable?</h5><p class="saswp-faq-answer-text">The coworking industry is growing rapidly and is expected to continue to grow in the coming years. This is due to a number of factors, including the rise of remote work, the increasing number of freelancers and entrepreneurs, and the need for more flexible workspaces.<br>The main source of revenue for coworking spaces is the rental of desks, meeting rooms, and private offices. Coworking spaces also generate revenue from other sources, such as event rentals, food and beverage sales, and merchandise sales.</p></ul></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/top-5-reasons-to-invest-in-coworking-spaces-in-2023/">Top 5 Reasons to Invest in Coworking Spaces in 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/planning/top-5-reasons-to-invest-in-coworking-spaces-in-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Invest In Coworking Space In India</title>
		<link>/planning/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=invest-in-coworking-space-in-india</link>
					<comments>/planning/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 08:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworking space investment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to Invest in Coworking Spaces in India Table of Contents The coworking space industry is growing rapidly in India, with new spaces opening up every day. This is due to a number of factors, including the increasing number of startups and freelancers, the rising cost of office space, and the growing demand for flexible &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/planning/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Invest In Coworking Space In India</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/">Invest In Coworking Space In India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="2448" height="1632" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-jpg.webp" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #67615e;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-jpg.webp 2448w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-300x200.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-1024x683.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-768x512.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-1536x1024.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-2048x1365.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2448px) 100vw, 2448px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="67615e" />		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="2833" class="elementor elementor-2833">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-ab90f0a elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="ab90f0a" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-e5614ad" data-id="e5614ad" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-7e7d5ad elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="7e7d5ad" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.16.0 - 09-10-2023 */
.elementor-heading-title{padding:0;margin:0;line-height:1}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title[class*=elementor-size-]>a{color:inherit;font-size:inherit;line-height:inherit}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-small{font-size:15px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-medium{font-size:19px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-large{font-size:29px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-xl{font-size:39px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-xxl{font-size:59px}</style><h1 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default"><strong>How to Invest in Coworking Spaces in India</strong></h1>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-a7d2814 elementor-widget elementor-widget-theme-post-featured-image elementor-widget-image" data-id="a7d2814" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="theme-post-featured-image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.16.0 - 09-10-2023 */
.elementor-widget-image{text-align:center}.elementor-widget-image a{display:inline-block}.elementor-widget-image a img[src$=".svg"]{width:48px}.elementor-widget-image img{vertical-align:middle;display:inline-block}</style>												<img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-1024x683.webp" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3088 not-transparent" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-1024x683.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-300x200.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-768x512.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-1536x1024.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Invest-Post-2048x1365.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="67615e" style="--dominant-color: #67615e" />															</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-25a185d elementor-toc--minimized-on-tablet elementor-widget elementor-widget-table-of-contents" data-id="25a185d" data-element_type="widget" data-settings="{&quot;exclude_headings_by_selector&quot;:[],&quot;marker_view&quot;:&quot;bullets&quot;,&quot;headings_by_tags&quot;:[&quot;h2&quot;,&quot;h3&quot;,&quot;h4&quot;,&quot;h5&quot;,&quot;h6&quot;],&quot;icon&quot;:{&quot;value&quot;:&quot;fas fa-circle&quot;,&quot;library&quot;:&quot;fa-solid&quot;},&quot;minimize_box&quot;:&quot;yes&quot;,&quot;minimized_on&quot;:&quot;tablet&quot;,&quot;hierarchical_view&quot;:&quot;yes&quot;,&quot;min_height&quot;:{&quot;unit&quot;:&quot;px&quot;,&quot;size&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;sizes&quot;:[]},&quot;min_height_tablet&quot;:{&quot;unit&quot;:&quot;px&quot;,&quot;size&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;sizes&quot;:[]},&quot;min_height_mobile&quot;:{&quot;unit&quot;:&quot;px&quot;,&quot;size&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;sizes&quot;:[]}}" data-widget_type="table-of-contents.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor-pro - v3.7.2 - 15-06-2022 */
.elementor-widget-table-of-contents .elementor-toc__header-title{color:var(--header-color)}.elementor-widget-table-of-contents.elementor-toc--collapsed .elementor-toc__toggle-button--collapse,.elementor-widget-table-of-contents:not(.elementor-toc--collapsed) .elementor-toc__toggle-button--expand{display:none}.elementor-widget-table-of-contents .elementor-widget-container{min-height:var(--box-min-height);border:var(--box-border-width,1px) solid var(--box-border-color,#a4afb7);border-radius:var(--box-border-radius,3px);background-color:var(--box-background-color);-webkit-transition:min-height .4s;-o-transition:min-height .4s;transition:min-height .4s;overflow:hidden}.elementor-toc__header{display:-webkit-box;display:-ms-flexbox;display:flex;-webkit-box-align:center;-ms-flex-align:center;align-items:center;-webkit-box-pack:justify;-ms-flex-pack:justify;justify-content:space-between;padding:var(--box-padding,20px);background-color:var(--header-background-color);border-bottom:var(--separator-width,1px) solid var(--box-border-color,#a4afb7)}.elementor-toc__header-title{font-size:18px;margin:0;color:var(--header-color)}.elementor-toc__toggle-button{cursor:pointer;display:-webkit-inline-box;display:-ms-inline-flexbox;display:inline-flex}.elementor-toc__toggle-button i{color:var(--toggle-button-color)}.elementor-toc__toggle-button svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:var(--toggle-button-color)}.elementor-toc__spinner-container{text-align:center}.elementor-toc__spinner{font-size:2em}.elementor-toc__spinner.e-font-icon-svg{height:1em;width:1em}.elementor-toc__body{padding:var(--box-padding,20px);max-height:var(--toc-body-max-height);overflow-y:auto}.elementor-toc__body::-webkit-scrollbar{width:7px}.elementor-toc__body::-webkit-scrollbar-thumb{background-color:#c2cbd2;border-radius:10px}.elementor-toc__list-wrapper{list-style:none;padding:0}.elementor-toc__list-item{margin-bottom:.5em}.elementor-toc__list-item.elementor-item-active{font-weight:700}.elementor-toc__list-item .elementor-toc__list-wrapper{margin-top:.5em;margin-left:var(--nested-list-indent,1em)}.elementor-toc__list-item-text:hover{color:var(--item-text-hover-color);-webkit-text-decoration:var(--item-text-hover-decoration);text-decoration:var(--item-text-hover-decoration)}.elementor-toc__list-item-text.elementor-item-active{color:var(--item-text-active-color);-webkit-text-decoration:var(--item-text-active-decoration);text-decoration:var(--item-text-active-decoration)}.elementor-toc__list-item-text-wrapper{display:-webkit-box;display:-ms-flexbox;display:flex;-webkit-box-align:center;-ms-flex-align:center;align-items:center}.elementor-toc__list-item-text-wrapper:before,.elementor-toc__list-item-text-wrapper i{margin-right:8px;color:var(--marker-color)}.elementor-toc__list-item-text-wrapper svg{margin-right:8px;fill:var(--marker-color);height:var(--marker-size,.5em);width:var(--marker-size,.5em)}.elementor-toc__list-item-text-wrapper i{font-size:var(--marker-size,.5em)}.elementor-toc__list-item-text-wrapper:before{font-size:var(--marker-size,1em)}.elementor-toc--content-ellipsis .elementor-toc__list-item-text{white-space:nowrap;overflow:hidden;-o-text-overflow:ellipsis;text-overflow:ellipsis}.elementor-toc__list-items--collapsible>.elementor-toc__list-wrapper>.elementor-toc__list-item>.elementor-toc__list-wrapper{display:none}.elementor-toc__heading-anchor{position:absolute}.elementor-toc__body .elementor-toc__list-item-text{color:var(--item-text-color);-webkit-text-decoration:var(--item-text-decoration);text-decoration:var(--item-text-decoration)}.elementor-toc__body .elementor-toc__list-item-text:hover{color:var(--item-text-hover-color);-webkit-text-decoration:var(--item-text-hover-decoration);text-decoration:var(--item-text-hover-decoration)}.elementor-toc__body .elementor-toc__list-item-text.elementor-item-active{color:var(--item-text-active-color);-webkit-text-decoration:var(--item-text-active-decoration);text-decoration:var(--item-text-active-decoration)}ol.elementor-toc__list-wrapper{counter-reset:item}ol.elementor-toc__list-wrapper .elementor-toc__list-item{counter-increment:item}ol.elementor-toc__list-wrapper .elementor-toc__list-item-text-wrapper:before{content:counters(item,".") ". "}</style>		<div class="elementor-toc__header">
			<h4 class="elementor-toc__header-title">
				Table of Contents			</h4>
							<div class="elementor-toc__toggle-button elementor-toc__toggle-button--expand"><i class="fas fa-chevron-down"></i></div>
				<div class="elementor-toc__toggle-button elementor-toc__toggle-button--collapse"><i class="fas fa-chevron-up"></i></div>
					</div>
		<div class="elementor-toc__body">
			<div class="elementor-toc__spinner-container">
				<i class="elementor-toc__spinner eicon-animation-spin eicon-loading" aria-hidden="true"></i>			</div>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-18603ab elementor-widget__width-initial elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="18603ab" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.16.0 - 09-10-2023 */
.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-stacked .elementor-drop-cap{background-color:#69727d;color:#fff}.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-framed .elementor-drop-cap{color:#69727d;border:3px solid;background-color:transparent}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap{margin-top:8px}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap-letter{width:1em;height:1em}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap{float:left;text-align:center;line-height:1;font-size:50px}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap-letter{display:inline-block}</style>				<p data-sourcepos="5:1-5:273">The coworking space industry is growing rapidly in India, with new spaces opening up every day. This is due to a number of factors, including the increasing number of startups and freelancers, the rising cost of office space, and the growing demand for flexible workspaces.</p><p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:105">If you are interested in investing in coworking spaces in India, there are a few things you need to know.</p><h2 data-sourcepos="9:1-9:47"><strong>Coworking Investment Ideas &amp; Advantages</strong></h2><p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:70">There are a few different ways to invest in coworking spaces. You can:</p><ul data-sourcepos="13:1-16:0"><li data-sourcepos="13:1-13:226"><h3><strong>Open your own Coworking Space.</strong></h3><p> This is the most involved option, but it also gives you the most control over the business. You will need to find a suitable location, lease the space, furnish it, and market it to tenants.</p></li><li data-sourcepos="14:1-14:224"><h3><strong>Invest in a Coworking Space Franchise.</strong></h3><p> This is a less risky option, as you will be partnering with a proven brand. There are a number of coworking space franchises available in India, such as WeWork, Regus, and CoWrkz.</p></li><li data-sourcepos="15:1-16:0"><h3><strong>Invest in a Coworking Space Real Estate Fund.</strong></h3><p> This is a way to invest in the coworking space industry without having to manage your own space. There are a number of coworking space real estate funds available in India, such as InnoVen Capital and CoHo Living.</p></li></ul><p data-sourcepos="17:1-17:116">No matter which option you choose, there are a number of advantages to investing in coworking spaces. These include:</p><ul data-sourcepos="19:1-22:0"><li data-sourcepos="19:1-19:255"><strong>High demand.</strong> The demand for coworking spaces is growing rapidly, so there is a good chance of your investment being successful. According to a report by JLL, the coworking space market in India is expected to grow at a CAGR of 25% from 2022 to 2027.</li><li data-sourcepos="20:1-20:253"><strong>High returns.</strong> The returns on investment in coworking spaces can be very high, especially in the early stages of the industry. A report by Knight Frank India found that the average return on investment for coworking space investors was 25% in 2021.</li><li data-sourcepos="21:1-22:0"><strong>Low risk.</strong> The risk of investing in coworking spaces is relatively low, as the industry is still in its early stages of growth. The coworking space industry is still relatively new in India, so there is less competition than in other countries.</li></ul><h3 data-sourcepos="23:1-23:43"><strong>Future of Coworking Investment In India</strong></h3><p data-sourcepos="25:1-25:394">The future of coworking investment in India looks bright. The industry is expected to continue to grow rapidly in the coming years, driven by the factors mentioned above. The increasing number of startups and freelancers, the rising cost of office space, and the growing demand for flexible workspaces are all factors that will contribute to the growth of the coworking space industry in India.</p><p data-sourcepos="27:1-27:101">If you are looking for a profitable investment opportunity, coworking spaces should be on your radar.</p><h3 data-sourcepos="29:1-29:89"><strong>Factors to Consider When Investing in Coworking Spaces in India:</strong></h3><ul data-sourcepos="31:1-36:0"><li data-sourcepos="31:1-31:152"><strong>Location:</strong> The location of the coworking space is critical to its success. It should be in a central location that is easily accessible to tenants.</li><li data-sourcepos="32:1-32:160"><strong>Amenities:</strong> The coworking space should offer a variety of amenities to attract tenants, such as high-speed internet, conference rooms, and coffee stations.</li><li data-sourcepos="33:1-33:100"><strong>Management:</strong> The coworking space should be well-managed and provide excellent customer service.</li><li data-sourcepos="34:1-34:145"><strong>Brand:</strong> If you are investing in a coworking space franchise, it is important to choose a brand that is well-known and has a good reputation.</li><li data-sourcepos="35:1-36:0"><strong>Market:</strong> It is important to research the coworking space market in the city or region where you plan to invest. This will help you to identify the demand for coworking spaces and the competition.</li></ul><h3 data-sourcepos="37:1-37:77"><strong>Risks Associated with Investing in Coworking Spaces:</strong></h3><ul data-sourcepos="39:1-42:0"><li data-sourcepos="39:1-39:209"><strong>High competition:</strong> The coworking space industry is becoming increasingly competitive. This means that it is important to choose a good location and offer competitive amenities in order to attract tenants.</li><li data-sourcepos="40:1-40:243"><strong>Fluctuating demand:</strong> The demand for coworking spaces can fluctuate depending on the economic climate. This means that it is important to do your research and choose a location that is likely to be in demand even during economic downturns.</li><li data-sourcepos="41:1-42:0"><strong>Operational costs:</strong> The operational costs of running a coworking space can be high. This includes the cost of rent, utilities, and staff. It is important to factor these costs into your investment analysis.</li></ul><p data-sourcepos="55:1-55:14"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p><p data-sourcepos="57:1-57:276">If you are considering investing in coworking spaces in India, there are a few things you need to keep in mind. Do your research, choose the right location, and manage the space well. With careful planning, you can make a profitable investment in the coworking space industry.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6ea91f0 elementor-widget elementor-widget-saswp-faq-block" data-id="6ea91f0" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="saswp-faq-block.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<ul><li style="list-style:none" class="elementor-repeater-item-4c5eaea"><h3>Is coworking space a good investment?</h3><p><p>Yes, coworking space can be a good investment. The industry is growing rapidly, and there is a high demand for flexible workspaces. However, as with any investment, there is always some risk involved.</p></p><li style="list-style:none" class="elementor-repeater-item-9f039f6"><h3>How to invest in coworking space?</h3><p><p data-sourcepos="37:1-37:69">There are a few different ways to invest in coworking space. You can:</p><ul data-sourcepos="39:1-42:0"><li data-sourcepos="39:1-39:32">Open your own coworking space.</li><li data-sourcepos="40:1-40:40">Invest in a coworking space franchise.</li><li data-sourcepos="41:1-42:0">Invest in a coworking space real estate fund.</li></ul></p><li style="list-style:none" class="elementor-repeater-item-b7ab8a2"><h3>Is coworking really the future?</h3><p><p>Yes, coworking is really the future of work. The traditional office model is becoming increasingly outdated, as more and more people are looking for flexible and collaborative workspaces.</p></p><li style="list-style:none" class="elementor-repeater-item-874b94d"><h3>Why do coworking spaces fail?</h3><p><p data-sourcepos="49:1-49:65">There are a few reasons why coworking spaces fail. These include:</p><ul data-sourcepos="51:1-54:0"><li data-sourcepos="51:1-51:153">Poor location. The location of the coworking space is critical to its success. It should be in a central location that is easily accessible to tenants.</li><li data-sourcepos="52:1-52:101">Poor management. The coworking space should be well-managed and provide excellent customer service.</li><li data-sourcepos="53:1-54:0">Lack of amenities. The coworking space should offer a variety of amenities to attract tenants, such as high-speed internet, conference rooms, and coffee stations.</li></ul></p></ul>		</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/">Invest In Coworking Space In India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/planning/invest-in-coworking-space-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What features make a coworking space the best type of workspace?</title>
		<link>/planning/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace</link>
					<comments>/planning/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Although each coworking space has its own individualized flair, the most successful spaces typically share a handful of common denominators. We&#8217;ve gathered intel from no. of coworking owners and operators to discover what really makes a good coworking space great. In this article, we&#8217;ll share this invaluable information with you and show you the ten &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/planning/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What features make a coworking space the best type of workspace?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/">What features make a coworking space the best type of workspace?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="2448" height="1632" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Coworking-Feature-jpg.webp" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #c2c8c6;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Coworking-Feature-jpg.webp 2448w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Coworking-Feature-300x200.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Coworking-Feature-1024x683.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Coworking-Feature-768x512.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Coworking-Feature-1536x1024.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Coworking-Feature-2048x1365.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2448px) 100vw, 2448px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="c2c8c6" />
<p>Although each coworking space has its own individualized flair, the most successful spaces typically share a handful of common denominators.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve gathered intel from no. of coworking owners and operators to discover what really makes a good coworking space great. In this article, we&#8217;ll share this invaluable information with you and show you the ten essential elements of every successful coworking space.</p>



<p>After learning what characteristics top-tier coworking spaces share, you&#8217;ll be able to take that knowledge and apply it to your own flexible workspace &#8211; transforming your business in the process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What should a coworking space have?</strong></h2>



<p>We compiled a list of ten qualities &#8211; both hard and soft &#8211; that we believe are essential for every coworking space. Listed in order of implementation, here they are:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A great leader</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Is one who is able to bring people together and create opportunities for them to connect. This ability to connect people often translates well into leadership skills.</p>



<p>One study from Harvard Business Review identified ten qualities that every leader should have, based on a survey administered to top leaders around the world. Those qualities were organized into the following themes:</p>



<p>A good coworking space leader:</p>



<ul>
<li>Demonstrates strong ethics and provides a sense of safety</li>



<li>Empowers others to self-organize</li>



<li>Fosters a sense of connection and belonging</li>



<li>Shows openness to new ideas and fosters organizational learning&nbsp;</li>



<li>Nurtures growth&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>Remember, you create the culture of your coworking space. A great leader is essential for any successful coworking space.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A clear mission</p>
</blockquote>



<p>A great leader always has a powerful mission that they can rally their team around. This is what a shared mission or set of values is for.</p>



<p>Some people might hear the word “mission” and think it has to be something really big or excessively hopeful. Even so, a regular mission can be just as influential as something more complicated.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important for companies to have a mission statement that resonates with their values and what they hope to achieve. Some of the most recognizable brands in the world have mission statements that reflect their goals, such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>Walmart: We save people money so they can live better</li>



<li>Sony: To be a company that inspires and fulfills your creativity</li>



<li>TED: To spread ideas</li>
</ul>



<p>No matter the size or scope, it&#8217;s important that your mission statement be something you and your team believe in wholeheartedly. This is what will resonate with your members and market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Your coworking space&#8217;s mission might be to bring people together, support small business owners, or provide childcare to working parents. By answering the question of why you&#8217;re starting a coworking space and who you&#8217;re hoping to serve, you can develop a statement that truly reflects the goals of your space.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A key differentiator</p>
</blockquote>



<p>A coworking space is a business, and every successful business has a unique selling proposition (USP).</p>



<p>Consumers are faced with a multitude of choices these days. It can be difficult for the average person to determine what makes your coworking space different from the seven others in your city. So, what is your USP? What makes your coworking space the best one for potential members?</p>



<p>Having a strong differentiator is important for any company so that they can stand out in their market. A great way to make your company more visible is by promoting your differentiator everywhere. The best differentiators are the ones that offer more than just the basics, like events or free coffee for members. Instead, try to think about things that will really appeal to your target demographic, such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>On-site childcare for working parents</li>



<li>A women’s-only space</li>



<li>Donating a portion of your revenue to local charities</li>



<li>Offering incubator services to tech start-ups&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>It’s important to make sure that your key differentiator aligns with both your mission statement and who you are trying to serve. This way, you can be sure that you are attracting the right kind of attention and business.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A strong brand</p>
</blockquote>



<p>A clear mission and key differentiator are two vital aspects that make up a coworking brand.</p>



<p>Many people tend to misunderstand that a brand is simply aesthetic, like a logo or website design. However, this couldn&#8217;t be any further from the truth. A brand is defined as &#8220;an intangible marketing or business concept that helps people identify a company, product, or individual&#8221;. In layman&#8217;s terms, it&#8217;s the emotional response you have when you think of a certain company.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important for coworking spaces to have a solidified brand because it sets them apart from the competitions and attracts members who fit with the space&#8217;s mission.</p>



<p>Your brand is your business&#8217;s identity. It&#8217;s how you make your members feel, the events you host, and everything in between. So, to build a strong brand, you need to make sure there&#8217;s consistency across all channels. Here are a few things that need to be on point:</p>



<ul>
<li>Design: Your design should reflect your mission and speak to your target market</li>



<li>Marketing: Your marketing strategy should align with what you value</li>



<li>Culture: Your culture should show how you feel about your community</li>



<li>Member experience: Your member experience should place value on your community</li>
</ul>



<p>By paying attention to these elements, you can begin to create a memorable coworking brand from the moment you open your doors.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A delightful user experience</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The modern workplace should revolve around the user experience. Too often, workspace operators view the user experience as an afterthought instead of understanding that it&#8217;s a journey. By focusing on the user experience, businesses can create a more efficient and enjoyable workplace.</p>



<p>From the very beginning, you need to think about the user experience, or the experience that your members have in your space. Start with the areas that are most important to your members:</p>



<p>Think about what your members care most about, or the areas of your business that are most frequented by your members. This could be payments, check-ins, or onboarding.</p>



<p>Then, determine how you can best serve them there: Brainstorm ways that you can provide your members with the absolute best experience in that specific area. What does a seamless check-in experience look like? How can you make payments easier?</p>



<p>A great user experience is one that&#8217;s memorable and positive from start to finish. To create a plan that will address these high-traffic touch points, consider how you can make each step of the user experience wonderful, and then put it into action.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A powerful technology stack</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The modern coworking space needs technology to stay afloat and compete against other coworking companies, big or small. By investing in technology, you&#8217;re opening up opportunities to streamline your operations, get detailed data measurements of your space usage, automate your business processes, and most importantly &#8211; create a delightful user experience for your members.</p>



<p>Technology can help you manage your coworking business with minimal overhead, so you can focus on more important things like growing your business and providing an elevated experience for your users.</p>



<p>Technology is an important aspect of any business looking to scale without necessarily scaling their costs. The earlier you can get it implemented in your space, the sooner it can start providing value and the less you’ll have to worry about migrating your members to a new technology down the road.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A truly flexible workspace</p>
</blockquote>



<p>A great coworking space is flexible in order to best suit the needs of their members. This means having a space that is accessible 24/7 with membership options that can be modified to fit the needs of each individual member. Also have a variety of seating options to allow people to work in the way that is most comfortable for them. Creating a flexible workspace means you are putting the needs of your members first. You are providing them with options and modifying your business to fit their needs rather than expecting them to change their lifestyle to fit yours.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&nbsp;A connected community</p>
</blockquote>



<p>You can bring people into your coworking space, but an important part of keeping a successful business is making sure those people stick around. Establishing a sense of community is one way to help with retention rates.</p>



<p>The most successful coworking spaces always have a thriving community because the members share common interests. They get something out of being around other like-minded individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Creating community starts with the basics, such as having a clear mission statement and providing an enjoyable experience for your members. If people feel like they belong somewhere, they are more likely to stay.</p>



<p>There are a few other tactics we commonly see operators use to create community:</p>



<ul>
<li>Hosting regular events</li>



<li>Creating networking opportunities between members</li>



<li>Your community resource partner</li>
</ul>



<p>Community is central to the coworking experience, with many members choosing coworking spaces specifically for that sense of community. Keep this in mind when building a connected space.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A plan to grow</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The best business owners always have an eye on the future. They know that in order to be successful in the long term, they need to do what they can now to set themselves up for success.</p>



<p>All of the best coworking spaces we&#8217;ve seen have a plan for growth. They know where they want to be and what they need to do to get there one day.</p>



<p>Create the best experience you can today, but don&#8217;t forget about the future. Have a plan for how your business can expand one day and grow into something really special.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A fantastic team</p>
</blockquote>



<p>You can do everything listed above, but you can’t do it alone.</p>



<p>The best coworking spaces all have a fantastic team of people behind them &#8211; people who are passionate, dedicated, enthusiastic, and 100% committed to creating something truly special for the people that walk through their doors. By having a great team behind you, you&#8217;re setting yourself up for success from the start.</p>



<p>Creating an excellent team starts with you. Check out these best practices for hiring your coworking staff:</p>



<ul>
<li>Start by writing detailed and accurate job descriptions</li>



<li>Then, post the jobs on well-known platforms and market them to attract the best talent</li>



<li>After that, build a great candidate interview process</li>



<li>And finally, use technology to enhance the experience, but make sure to include face-to-face interactions</li>



<li>Hiring a top-notch team is an exhilarating first step in developing a strong company culture.</li>
</ul>



<p>Creating a vibrant and unforgettable coworking experience for your members starts with laying a strong foundation in your space.</p>



<p>factors like fostering a connected community, creating a great user experience across all touchpoints, and establishing a recognizable brand are all integral to creating a wonderful coworking space.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Click here to learn more about creating an impactful coworking space.</a></p>



<p><strong>Hire a good Team</strong></p>



<p>Lastly, if you want to run a successful<strong>&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.propques.com/start-coworking-business/"><strong>coworking business</strong></a>, then you must do it with a great team. You need to make sure you hire people who understand this business as well as you do. You need to make sure they have all the necessary skills required and that they have a personality which matches with the community that you plan to create.</p>



<p>The steps you take are very crucial because they will decide the success or failure of your business. If you need any assistance in starting your coworking business, then, do consider reaching out to our team because here at Propques, we have a panel of experienced professions who can help simplify the process of starting your business and turn your business profitable.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/">What features make a coworking space the best type of workspace?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/planning/what-features-make-a-coworking-space-the-best-type-of-workspace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to add coworking to your CRE Property</title>
		<link>/planning/how-to-add-coworking-to-your-cre-property/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-add-coworking-to-your-cre-property</link>
					<comments>/planning/how-to-add-coworking-to-your-cre-property/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is the future of coworking, flex spaces, &#38; commercial real estate? In the aftermath of the COVID pandemic and an increase in corporate work-from-home policies, the commercial real estate market is due for a huge shift. Coworking and flex spaces have evolved to provide customized high-demand spaces for Fortune 500 companies, and savvy CRE &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/planning/how-to-add-coworking-to-your-cre-property/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to add coworking to your CRE Property</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/how-to-add-coworking-to-your-cre-property/">How to add coworking to your CRE Property</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="2448" height="1836" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/CRE-Property-jpg.webp" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #667579;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/CRE-Property-jpg.webp 2448w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/CRE-Property-300x225.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/CRE-Property-1024x768.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/CRE-Property-768x576.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/CRE-Property-1536x1152.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/CRE-Property-2048x1536.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2448px) 100vw, 2448px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="667579" />
<p><strong>What is the future of coworking, flex spaces, &amp; commercial real estate?</strong></p>



<p>In the aftermath of the COVID pandemic and an increase in corporate work-from-home policies, the commercial real estate market is due for a huge shift. Coworking and flex spaces have evolved to provide customized high-demand spaces for Fortune 500 companies, and savvy CRE investors can stay ahead of the curve by converting their portfolio vacancies to profitable coworking/flex spaces.</p>



<p><strong>From desks-for-rent to outsourced hospitality for SMBs/enterprise</strong></p>



<p>What do you picture when you think of “coworking”? Websites and stock photos often depict groups of young, attractive colleagues working in long rows of shared desks, sitting on couches with laptops and working in between foosball matches. But in reality, coworking — or at least that version of it — is no longer driving profit for flex space providers. The rapid growth of firms such as WeWork, Regus, AWFIS, Smartworks and others now has almost everything to do with serving the basic office needs of local SMBs and established corporations like Amazon, ICICI Bank and Accenture. What’s been branded as a revolutionary answer to office life in the 21st century now more closely resembles a business model that’s been around for decades: commercial property management.</p>



<p><strong>How to add coworking to your CRE property</strong></p>



<p>We can make it happen.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques consulting team</a>&nbsp;can put together the elements you need to fill your property with a long-lasting and profitable coworking business. From feasibility reports, matchmaking with the right operator or franchise, and pre- and post-launch consulting to ensure you’re set for success.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title=""><strong>Feasibility &amp; Focus Research</strong></a></p>



<p>Let’s figure out whether coworking is right for you. Our team will review your particular property and market, and create an actionable plan.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Validation</strong>: Are there enough available customers in nearby zip codes to convert the property to coworking?</li>



<li><strong>Buildout</strong>: What type of furniture should you buy to for your customers, and what is the estimated cost for your goals?</li>



<li><strong>Client focus</strong>: What should you focus on – remote workers, small businesses, or corporate clients?</li>



<li><strong>Pricing</strong>: How much can you charge for desks and offices in your location?</li>



<li><strong>Competition</strong>: What is your expected growth rate and time-to-profitability based on the local market?</li>



<li><strong>Amenities</strong>: What provides better ROIs – standard coffee service, sparkling water on tap, podcasting studios, or something new?</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Matchmaking with Coworking Operators</strong></p>



<p>Looking beyond the brokered lease?&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;can connect you to our network of coworking owner/operators and find the perfect fit for your space.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Management Contracts</a></em></p>



<p>In the post-COVID, post-WeWork, Awfis etc more and more property owners are turning to management contracts to reduce risk and share in the profits. Propques can guide you in selecting the right contract and make introductions to potential operators.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Joint Ventures &amp; Franchise</a></em></p>



<p>Traditionally used by entrepreneurs in the know, property owners can leverage partnerships and franchises to hand off day-to-day responsibility and bring additional expertise to the table. We’ll help make it happen.</p>



<p>The process of finding the right partner for a profitable long-term business venture is more complicated than the traditional brokered lease.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">Propques</a>&nbsp;matchmaking service tackles those problems for you by researching and forecasting future performance by our coworking consultants, connecting you to our network of property owners and coworking operators, and overseeing the project and integration to ensure success.</p>



<p>STEP 1 :&nbsp;<strong>Research, Forecasting, and Financial Modeling</strong></p>



<p><strong>We’ll assess and run the numbers.</strong></p>



<p>We create extensive proformas, market &amp; feasibility analyses, and create guidance documents that inspire confidence moving forward.</p>



<p>STEP 2 :&nbsp;<strong>Partner Vetting and Matchmaking</strong></p>



<p><strong>We’ll find and vet potential partners.</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>No unproven partners, no surprises down the line. We make sure our extensive network is qualified and primed for success.</p>



<p>STEP 3 :&nbsp;<strong>Legal Frameworks and Process Management</strong></p>



<p><strong>We’ll guide the project to completion.</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have framework documents so you’re not starting from scratch, and we keep all parties moving ahead with concrete steps.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.propques.com/" title=""><strong>We’ll find your perfect match.</strong></a></h3>



<p>We charge a fixed rate per sqft for property owners – typically less than the traditional commercial brokerage fee. There’s never a charge for coworking operators to get matched. Reach out today and let’s see how we can help.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/how-to-add-coworking-to-your-cre-property/">How to add coworking to your CRE Property</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/planning/how-to-add-coworking-to-your-cre-property/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</title>
		<link>/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision-2/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision-2</link>
					<comments>/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 12:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We’ll take a look at what you need to cover to build a financial model you can have confidence in. And that&#8217;s what business plans and financial models are all about &#8211; confidence. Confidence you&#8217;ve got the numbers in the right ballpark, so you can happily take on the commitment of a lease and the &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision-2/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision-2/">How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="2448" height="1632" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Decision-Making-jpg.webp" class="attachment-full size-full not-transparent wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="--dominant-color: #99918c;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Decision-Making-jpg.webp 2448w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Decision-Making-300x200.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Decision-Making-1024x683.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Decision-Making-768x512.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Decision-Making-1536x1024.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Decision-Making-2048x1365.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2448px) 100vw, 2448px" data-has-transparency="false" data-dominant-color="99918c" />
<p>We’ll take a look at what you need to cover to build a financial model you can have confidence in.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what business plans and financial models are all about &#8211; confidence.</p>



<p>Confidence you&#8217;ve got the numbers in the right ballpark, so you can happily take on the commitment of a lease and the fit-out.</p>



<p>The core things to cover are:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Pricing&nbsp;</strong>(Competitor Analysis and Local Market Review)</li>



<li><strong>Break Down of Space Allocation</strong></li>



<li><strong>Revenue Model</strong></li>



<li><strong>Cost of Sales&nbsp;</strong>(property costs)<strong>&nbsp;and Operating Expenditure</strong></li>



<li><strong>Customer Acquisition Costs</strong>&nbsp;(CACs)</li>



<li><strong>Estimate of how long it takes to reach break-even</strong>&nbsp;(and mature occupancy)</li>



<li><strong>Profit and Loss</strong></li>



<li><strong>Capital required for project</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>There’s a lot more you could include on the financial side (balance sheet, cash flow). And a full business plan might also need things like SWOT analysis, brand positioning, and breakdown of marketing channels.</p>



<p>But for the purposes of this piece we’re just going to focus on the key commercials.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Pricing (Competitor Analysis &amp; Local Market Review)</strong></h2>



<p>In order to have an idea of pricing, you’ll need to have a rough idea of who your target market is and what you’ll be selling them (private offices vs dedicated desks vs hot desks). The easiest way to start that process is to ground it in some good old-fashioned competitor research.</p>



<p>Of course, you don&#8217;t need to be constrained by the competition and what has/hasn&#8217;t worked for them. But it&#8217;s certainly helpful as a starting point to figure out your customer, product, and pricing.</p>



<p>As well as looking at workspaces in your geographic area, it’s worth also looking at spaces that are of interest from the perspective of size (sq ft), operating model, target market, amenities offered, brand, and culture. This will be particularly important if you’re launching in an unproven location that doesn’t have any direct comparables.</p>



<p>There are lots of ways you could go about this, but reviewing coworking spaces on broker sites&nbsp;is always a good place to start.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Breakdown of Space Allocation</strong></h2>



<p>Even if you haven&#8217;t yet found a building it’s important to have an idea of how you will lay out the space. So come up with a number for the total sq ft that you think would be optimal to work with (e.g. 15000 sqft), and go from there.</p>



<p>This ‘optimal’ size can act as the starting template for you to work off. When you find a building it’s unlikely to be exactly the same sq ft as your optimal size. Maybe a landlord shows you a 13,000 sq ft or 17,000 sq ft site. But as long as you have attributed a % to each specific space use, you can easily tweak the model depending on the actual building you find.</p>



<p>When you do look for a building you’ll be told the size in either SBA ( Super Built Area) or CA ( Carpet Area). I would always try to work off the Carpet Area as it excludes internal walls and non-usable spaces, which can vary a lot from building to building.</p>



<p>You’ll then need to figure out how much sq ft you’ll be providing for the following:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Workspace</h3>



<ul>
<li>Private Offices</li>



<li>Dedicated Desks</li>



<li>Hot Desks</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Ancillary</h3>



<ul>
<li>Meeting rooms</li>



<li>Phone booths</li>



<li>Storage</li>



<li>Break out space</li>



<li>Events space</li>



<li>Kitchen</li>



<li>Cafe/bar/restaurant</li>



<li>Reception</li>



<li>IT and printing</li>



<li>Circulation</li>



<li>Any other niche offering (nap pods, podcast booths, etc.)</li>
</ul>



<p>The temptation will always be to put in as many desks as possible! But of course, the more cramped the workspace feels the less enjoyable the membership experience will be, and the harder it will be to fill. So getting that balance right is very important.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Revenue Model</strong></h2>



<p>Once you know how you’re using the space, you’ll know what the capacity is in the building at any one time and therefore how many desks you can fit in. For example, if your optimal building is 15,000 sq ft, and your density is 40 sq ft per person, then that means you can have 375 desks.</p>



<p>Figuring out how many Dedicated Desk and Private Office members are available for sale is simple. You simply have the same number of memberships available as you have desks.</p>



<p>But figuring out the number of hot-desking memberships is a little more complex, because you can of course over book these seats, just like you would overbook gym memberships. And as well as the designated hot desks, you also have the overflow space in break-out areas.</p>



<p>The multiple by which you can overbook hot-desking memberships will entirely depend on your model. It could be anywhere between 125% &#8211; 300%. 300% assumes if you had 10 hot desk seats you could sell 30 hot desk memberships. This would be predicated off your hot desk members not using the space very much.</p>



<p>Once you know the total number of memberships available for sale, you’ll then need to estimate the occupancy.</p>



<p>Again, this will depend on your model. But a reasonable target is 85%. Remember that 100% is hard to achieve even with a waiting list. By nature flexible workspaces are easy come and easy go; so when a company does go you may not have much warning or time to line up a replacement.</p>



<p>Inevitably you’ll be playing a game of musical chairs &#8211; managing the incoming and outgoing companies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A quick word on Additional Revenue</strong></h3>



<p>There are a number of additional ways you can monetize your space, beyond merely selling coworking memberships. You’ll need to decide what’s included in the membership price and what members need to pay extra for. Here are some of the typical ways you might make additional revenue, beyond the desk memberships:</p>



<ul>
<li>Virtual Office memberships (mail handling, forwarding, scanning)</li>



<li>Virtual PA services (call handling etc)</li>



<li>Bandwidth packages</li>



<li>Printing</li>



<li>Telecoms (VoIP phones etc)</li>



<li>Partnerships and referrals</li>



<li>Meeting room hire</li>



<li>Event space hire</li>



<li>Online marketplace</li>



<li>Wellness treatments + events</li>



<li>F&amp;B</li>
</ul>



<p>You can potentially achieve 10% &#8211; 25% additional revenue from these other sources. So it’s worth having a plan to include some of them, even if they’re not the backbone of your business.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Cost of Sales and Operating Expenditure</strong></h2>



<p>Now you have an estimate of what revenue you’ll make, it’s time to figure out what the costs will be. For various reasons, it’s often helpful to separate the fixed property costs and the business operating costs.</p>



<p>So when it comes to setting up your P&amp;L sheet, I’d recommend sticking the property costs under ‘Cost of Sales’ (COS) and everything else (all the business operating costs) in the ‘Operating Expenditure’ (OpEx).</p>



<p>On that basis&#8230;</p>



<p>These things would be included in the COS:</p>



<ul>
<li>Rent (assuming you are taking a traditional lease from a landlord)</li>



<li>Rates (business rates / council tax)</li>



<li>Service Charge (this is a charge from the landlord)</li>
</ul>



<p>And all the other costs of operating the business would be included in the OpEx:</p>



<ul>
<li>Accounting</li>



<li>Cleaning</li>



<li>Events + Programming</li>



<li>Internet</li>



<li>Marketing (see ‘Customer Acquisition Costs’ below)</li>



<li>Printing and stationary</li>



<li>Repairs and maintenance</li>



<li>Software</li>



<li>Staffing (after your rent, this is the most significant cost)</li>



<li>Supplies</li>



<li>Utilities</li>



<li>Etc.</li>
</ul>



<p>A word to the wise….flexible workspaces are typically quite operationally intensive. So even if you have a fairly low-touch model, you may be surprised by how much goes into successfully operating these spaces, and the associated costs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Customer Acquisition Costs</strong></h2>



<p>One of the most common misconceptions among newbies to coworking is that you just need to ‘build it and they will come’. The hope being that if you’re in a prominent location, and you’ve built a great workspace, then people will just magically waltz through your door and sign up.</p>



<p>Sadly, even with a stellar workspace in a highly sought after location, you still need to get the word out and engage with your target audience. In other words, you need a marketing budget.</p>



<p>The cost of acquiring members is sometimes easy to track (e.g. if a large company who wants a private office comes via a broker or a paid Google Ad), other times it’s less easy to track (perhaps a freelancer takes a hot desk after they’ve come across a blog post you’ve written). But whether it’s easy or hard to track, there’s always a cost.</p>



<p>Knowing your ‘Customer Acquisition Cost’ will not only inform your marketing budget, but it will also help you track which marketing channel is working best once you launch.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Estimate of how long it takes to reach break even (and mature occupancy)</strong></h2>



<p>Estimating how long it will take to fill the space at the beginning is important for two reasons.</p>



<p>Firstly &#8211; it’s necessary because there will be an initial shortfall of cash that you will need to allow for. Before the space breaks even your costs will exceed your revenue and knowing how long this could take will inform the size of the cash float you need to start off with.</p>



<p>Secondly &#8211; having a realistic estimate of how long the space takes to fill will help you not panic! Sometimes workspaces can take 2 years to reach maturity, but then once they do reach their target they remain steady and profitable. So knowing that will give you some cause for calm in the initial stages of growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Profit and Loss</strong></h2>



<p>Once you have figured out your revenue, property costs (COS) and operating expenses (OpEx) you’ll be able to calculate the profit (EBITDA):</p>



<p>(Revenue) &#8211; (COS) &#8211; (OpEx) = Profit</p>



<p>How many years you build out for the Profit and Loss sheet will depend on your model. But my guess is it needs to be somewhere between 5-15 years. Remember to factor in refurbishments (which will be necessary every 5-7 years).</p>



<p>It’s also a good idea to have a tab on your spreadsheet that also shows the P&amp;L in INR /sq ft. That will help you compare the profitability of different sized venues.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How much money will you need to launch?</strong></h2>



<p>In terms of how much capital expenditure (‘CapEx’) is needed to get the project off the ground, here’s what you need to budget for:</p>



<ul>
<li>Fit Out</li>



<li>Cash float to cover costs during initial growth stages</li>



<li>Other Site Set Up Costs</li>



<li>Central Setup Costs</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Fit Out</strong></h3>



<p>This is obviously the biggie. And in honesty it’s hard to estimate it unless you have a real-life building to base your numbers on. Even then you’ll want to get some expert advice to give you cost estimates.</p>



<p>That said, you can of course get approximate benchmarks for the various components that make up the fit out of a coworking space. These components include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Category A works</li>



<li>Category B works</li>



<li>Furniture, Fixtures and Equipment (FF&amp;E)</li>



<li>IT + AV equipment</li>



<li>Signage and artwork</li>



<li>Contingency</li>
</ul>



<p>The costs for the fit out will depend on the specification you need and the density you’re working to.</p>



<p>It will also depend on whether you want to take space that is in a ‘Shell and Core’ state (ie it needs all the work done on it) or whether you want to take space that has already had the ‘Category A’ works completed by the landlord.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Cash float to cover costs during initial growth stages</strong></h3>



<p>As previously mentioned, you will have an initial growth period where your costs exceed your revenue. And you’ll need a cash float to cover this.</p>



<p>It’s a good idea to be conservative in your estimations, and to have a number of other levers you can pull should the space fill slower than you expected.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Other Site Set Up Costs</strong></h3>



<p>These are the costs associated with launching the site that aren’t anything to do with the fit out. They include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Legal fees for the lease</li>



<li>Pre-lease building survey</li>



<li>Health and safety risk assessment</li>



<li>Hiring and training the team (Community Managers)</li>



<li>Venue photography</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Central Set Up Costs</strong></h3>



<p>If this is your first site and you’re setting up a coworking operation from scratch, then you’ll also need to factor in the following:</p>



<ul>
<li>Membership Contracts (Terms and Conditions + House Rules)</li>



<li>Branding</li>



<li>Website and tech stack</li>



<li>Setting up processes and systems for everything</li>



<li>Other administrative costs of setting up a business + bank account</li>
</ul>



<p>Lastly…</p>



<p>Inevitably, like any business plan, and no matter what level of forensic detail you go into, you’ll get some numbers right and some numbers wrong.</p>



<p>But as long as you come up with sensible estimates, based on benchmarks and a sound rationale, then you have every hope that you’ll find yourself in the right ballpark.</p>



<p>Good luck with it. And if I can help in any way (either officially or just a friendly chin wag) then please feel free to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/" title="">get in touch&#8230;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision-2/">How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</title>
		<link>/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision</link>
					<comments>/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh Dixit - Flexible Workspace Specialist]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 06:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We’ll take a look at what you need to cover to build a financial model you can have confidence in. And that’s what business plans and financial models are all about – confidence. Confidence you’ve got the numbers in the right ballpark, so you can happily take on the commitment of a lease and the &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision/">How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="752" height="423" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/1677229269359.png" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" alt="interior of a coworking space" decoding="async" style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/1677229269359.png 752w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/1677229269359-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 752px) 100vw, 752px" />
<p>We’ll take a look at what you need to cover to build a financial model you can have confidence in.</p>



<p>And that’s what business plans and financial models are all about – confidence.</p>



<p>Confidence you’ve got the numbers in the right ballpark, so you can happily take on the commitment of a lease and the fit-out.</p>



<p>The core things to cover are:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Pricing&nbsp;</strong>(Competitor Analysis and Local Market Review)</li>



<li><strong>Break Down of Space Allocation</strong></li>



<li><strong>Revenue Model</strong></li>



<li><strong>Cost of Sales&nbsp;</strong>(property costs)<strong>&nbsp;and Operating Expenditure</strong></li>



<li><strong>Customer Acquisition Costs</strong>&nbsp;(CACs)</li>



<li><strong>Estimate of how long it takes to reach break-even</strong>&nbsp;(and mature occupancy)</li>



<li><strong>Profit and Loss</strong></li>



<li><strong>Capital required for project</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>There’s a lot more you could include on the financial side (balance sheet, cash flow). And a full business plan might also need things like SWOT analysis, brand positioning, and breakdown of marketing channels.</p>



<p>But for the purposes of this piece we’re just going to focus on the key commercials.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Pricing (Competitor Analysis &amp; Local Market Review)</strong></h2>



<p>In order to have an idea of pricing, you’ll need to have a rough idea of who your target market is and what you’ll be selling them (private offices vs dedicated desks vs hot desks). The easiest way to start that process is to ground it in some good old-fashioned competitor research.</p>



<p>Of course, you don’t need to be constrained by the competition and what has/hasn’t worked for them. But it’s certainly helpful as a starting point to figure out your customer, product, and pricing.</p>



<p>As well as looking at workspaces in your geographic area, it’s worth also looking at spaces that are of interest from the perspective of size (sq ft), operating model, target market, amenities offered, brand, and culture. This will be particularly important if you’re launching in an unproven location that doesn’t have any direct comparables.</p>



<p>There are lots of ways you could go about this, but reviewing coworking spaces on broker sites&nbsp;is always a good place to start.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Breakdown of Space Allocation</strong></h2>



<p>Even if you haven’t yet found a building it’s important to have an idea of how you will lay out the space. So come up with a number for the total sq ft that you think would be optimal to work with (e.g. 15000 sqft), and go from there.</p>



<p>This ‘optimal’ size can act as the starting template for you to work off. When you find a building it’s unlikely to be exactly the same sq ft as your optimal size. Maybe a landlord shows you a 13,000 sq ft or 17,000 sq ft site. But as long as you have attributed a % to each specific space use, you can easily tweak the model depending on the actual building you find.</p>



<p>When you do look for a building you’ll be told the size in either SBA ( Super Built Area) or CA ( Carpet Area). I would always try to work off the Carpet Area as it excludes internal walls and non-usable spaces, which can vary a lot from building to building.</p>



<p>You’ll then need to figure out how much sq ft you’ll be providing for the following:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Workspace</h3>



<ul>
<li>Private Offices</li>



<li>Dedicated Desks</li>



<li>Hot Desks</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Ancillary</h3>



<ul>
<li>Meeting rooms</li>



<li>Phone booths</li>



<li>Storage</li>



<li>Break out space</li>



<li>Events space</li>



<li>Kitchen</li>



<li>Cafe/bar/restaurant</li>



<li>Reception</li>



<li>IT and printing</li>



<li>Circulation</li>



<li>Any other niche offering (nap pods, podcast booths, etc.)</li>
</ul>



<p>The temptation will always be to put in as many desks as possible! But of course, the more cramped the workspace feels the less enjoyable the membership experience will be, and the harder it will be to fill. So getting that balance right is very important.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Revenue Model</strong></h2>



<p>Once you know how you’re using the space, you’ll know what the capacity is in the building at any one time and therefore how many desks you can fit in. For example, if your optimal building is 15,000 sq ft, and your density is 40 sq ft per person, then that means you can have 375 desks.</p>



<p>Figuring out how many Dedicated Desk and Private Office members are available for sale is simple. You simply have the same number of memberships available as you have desks.</p>



<p>But figuring out the number of hot-desking memberships is a little more complex, because you can of course over book these seats, just like you would overbook gym memberships. And as well as the designated hot desks, you also have the overflow space in break-out areas.</p>



<p>The multiple by which you can overbook hot-desking memberships will entirely depend on your model. It could be anywhere between 125% – 300%. 300% assumes if you had 10 hot desk seats you could sell 30 hot desk memberships. This would be predicated off your hot desk members not using the space very much.</p>



<p>Once you know the total number of memberships available for sale, you’ll then need to estimate the occupancy.</p>



<p>Again, this will depend on your model. But a reasonable target is 85%. Remember that 100% is hard to achieve even with a waiting list. By nature flexible workspaces are easy come and easy go; so when a company does go you may not have much warning or time to line up a replacement.</p>



<p>Inevitably you’ll be playing a game of musical chairs – managing the incoming and outgoing companies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A quick word on Additional Revenue</strong></h3>



<p>There are a number of additional ways you can monetize your space, beyond merely selling coworking memberships. You’ll need to decide what’s included in the membership price and what members need to pay extra for. Here are some of the typical ways you might make additional revenue, beyond the desk memberships:</p>



<ul>
<li>Virtual Office memberships (mail handling, forwarding, scanning)</li>



<li>Virtual PA services (call handling etc)</li>



<li>Bandwidth packages</li>



<li>Printing</li>



<li>Telecoms (VoIP phones etc)</li>



<li>Partnerships and referrals</li>



<li>Meeting room hire</li>



<li>Event space hire</li>



<li>Online marketplace</li>



<li>Wellness treatments + events</li>



<li>F&amp;B</li>
</ul>



<p>You can potentially achieve 10% – 25% additional revenue from these other sources. So it’s worth having a plan to include some of them, even if they’re not the backbone of your business.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Cost of Sales and Operating Expenditure</strong></h2>



<p>Now you have an estimate of what revenue you’ll make, it’s time to figure out what the costs will be. For various reasons, it’s often helpful to separate the fixed property costs and the business operating costs.</p>



<p>So when it comes to setting up your P&amp;L sheet, I’d recommend sticking the property costs under ‘Cost of Sales’ (COS) and everything else (all the business operating costs) in the ‘Operating Expenditure’ (OpEx).</p>



<p>On that basis…</p>



<p>These things would be included in the COS:</p>



<ul>
<li>Rent (assuming you are taking a traditional lease from a landlord)</li>



<li>Rates (business rates / council tax)</li>



<li>Service Charge (this is a charge from the landlord)</li>
</ul>



<p>And all the other costs of operating the business would be included in the OpEx:</p>



<ul>
<li>Accounting</li>



<li>Cleaning</li>



<li>Events + Programming</li>



<li>Internet</li>



<li>Marketing (see ‘Customer Acquisition Costs’ below)</li>



<li>Printing and stationary</li>



<li>Repairs and maintenance</li>



<li>Software</li>



<li>Staffing (after your rent, this is the most significant cost)</li>



<li>Supplies</li>



<li>Utilities</li>



<li>Etc.</li>
</ul>



<p>A word to the wise….flexible workspaces are typically quite operationally intensive. So even if you have a fairly low-touch model, you may be surprised by how much goes into successfully operating these spaces, and the associated costs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Customer Acquisition Costs</strong></h2>



<p>One of the most common misconceptions among newbies to coworking is that you just need to ‘build it and they will come’. The hope being that if you’re in a prominent location, and you’ve built a great workspace, then people will just magically waltz through your door and sign up.</p>



<p>Sadly, even with a stellar workspace in a highly sought after location, you still need to get the word out and engage with your target audience. In other words, you need a marketing budget.</p>



<p>The cost of acquiring members is sometimes easy to track (e.g. if a large company who wants a private office comes via a broker or a paid Google Ad), other times it’s less easy to track (perhaps a freelancer takes a hot desk after they’ve come across a blog post you’ve written). But whether it’s easy or hard to track, there’s always a cost.</p>



<p>Knowing your ‘Customer Acquisition Cost’ will not only inform your marketing budget, but it will also help you track which marketing channel is working best once you launch.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Estimate of how long it takes to reach break even (and mature occupancy)</strong></h2>



<p>Estimating how long it will take to fill the space at the beginning is important for two reasons.</p>



<p>Firstly – it’s necessary because there will be an initial shortfall of cash that you will need to allow for. Before the space breaks even your costs will exceed your revenue and knowing how long this could take will inform the size of the cash float you need to start off with.</p>



<p>Secondly – having a realistic estimate of how long the space takes to fill will help you not panic! Sometimes workspaces can take 2 years to reach maturity, but then once they do reach their target they remain steady and profitable. So knowing that will give you some cause for calm in the initial stages of growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Profit and Loss</strong></h2>



<p>Once you have figured out your revenue, property costs (COS) and operating expenses (OpEx) you’ll be able to calculate the profit (EBITDA):</p>



<p>(Revenue) – (COS) – (OpEx) = Profit</p>



<p>How many years you build out for the Profit and Loss sheet will depend on your model. But my guess is it needs to be somewhere between 5-15 years. Remember to factor in refurbishments (which will be necessary every 5-7 years).</p>



<p>It’s also a good idea to have a tab on your spreadsheet that also shows the P&amp;L in INR /sq ft. That will help you compare the profitability of different sized venues.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How much money will you need to launch?</strong></h2>



<p>In terms of how much capital expenditure (‘CapEx’) is needed to get the project off the ground, here’s what you need to budget for:</p>



<ul>
<li>Fit Out</li>



<li>Cash float to cover costs during initial growth stages</li>



<li>Other Site Set Up Costs</li>



<li>Central Setup Costs</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Fit Out</strong></h3>



<p>This is obviously the biggie. And in honesty it’s hard to estimate it unless you have a real-life building to base your numbers on. Even then you’ll want to get some expert advice to give you cost estimates.</p>



<p>That said, you can of course get approximate benchmarks for the various components that make up the fit out of a coworking space. These components include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Category A works</li>



<li>Category B works</li>



<li>Furniture, Fixtures and Equipment (FF&amp;E)</li>



<li>IT + AV equipment</li>



<li>Signage and artwork</li>



<li>Contingency</li>
</ul>



<p>The costs for the fit out will depend on the specification you need and the density you’re working to.</p>



<p>It will also depend on whether you want to take space that is in a ‘Shell and Core’ state (ie it needs all the work done on it) or whether you want to take space that has already had the ‘Category A’ works completed by the landlord.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Cash float to cover costs during initial growth stages</strong></h3>



<p>As previously mentioned, you will have an initial growth period where your costs exceed your revenue. And you’ll need a cash float to cover this.</p>



<p>It’s a good idea to be conservative in your estimations, and to have a number of other levers you can pull should the space fill slower than you expected.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Other Site Set Up Costs</strong></h3>



<p>These are the costs associated with launching the site that aren’t anything to do with the fit out. They include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Legal fees for the lease</li>



<li>Pre-lease building survey</li>



<li>Health and safety risk assessment</li>



<li>Hiring and training the team (Community Managers)</li>



<li>Venue photography</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Central Set Up Costs</strong></h3>



<p>If this is your first site and you’re setting up a coworking operation from scratch, then you’ll also need to factor in the following:</p>



<ul>
<li>Membership Contracts (Terms and Conditions + House Rules)</li>



<li>Branding</li>



<li>Website and tech stack</li>



<li>Setting up processes and systems for everything</li>



<li>Other administrative costs of setting up a business + bank account</li>
</ul>



<p>Lastly…</p>



<p>Inevitably, like any business plan, and no matter what level of forensic detail you go into, you’ll get some numbers right and some numbers wrong.</p>



<p>But as long as you come up with sensible estimates, based on benchmarks and a sound rationale, then you have every hope that you’ll find yourself in the right ballpark.</p>



<p>Good luck with it. And if I can help in any way (either officially or just a friendly chin wag) then please feel free to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.propques.com/">get in touch…</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision/">How to build a financial model for your coworking space ( Right Data _Right Decision )</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Propques</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/planning/how-to-build-a-financial-model-for-your-coworking-space-right-data-_right-decision/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
